佳家高清，国内最全最新高清影视资源库就在您身边！
请加QQ：1073737340获取最新高清影视目录，谢谢！
进来
Come in.
斯班塞先生
很抱歉打扰你
Mr Spencer.
Mr Spencer, I hate to bother you...
有两个男人来过
but I thought you'd like to know
there were two men here.
说是找你的
Two men askin' for you.
一个年轻人
另一个老些
A young man and a kind of older man.
我说你不在
他们好像不高兴
They was sorry you wasn't in.
I said you wasn't.
-他们有说会再来吗?
-没说但我想他们会再来的
- Did they say they'd be back?
- They didn't say, but I think they will.
刚才我出去买东西的时候
看见他们在拐角那里等著
Just now, when I had to go to the store,
I seen them standing there at the corner.
也许我应该让他们进来
但不能打扰你
Maybe I shoulda let them in,
only you said not to disturb you -
-是吗?
-我觉得他们会再来的
- Yes.
- And I'm sure They'll be back.
你样子看上去很疲惫啊
You look kinda tired to me,
and that's a fact.
有些头疼吗?
You got a headache or somethin'?
我想你应该好好休息一下了
I think maybe you need a real rest.
That's what I think.
斯班塞先生
你不该把钱到处放
Why, Mr Spencer. You oughtn't to leave
all that money lying around like that.
看到这样我觉得很不自然
Oh, it makes me nervous
to see money lying around.
世界上不是
所有人都是诚实的
Everybody in the world
ain't honest, you know.
但你可以相信我
我是很诚实的
Though I must say I haven't had
much trouble that way.
你的一些朋友打电话来了
还叫我不要告诉你
Those friends of yours
told me not to mention they'd called.
说想给你一个惊喜
但我还是要说一声
Wanted to surprise you. But I thought
you'd like to know somehow.
是啊当然了如果他们
再来就让他们进来吧
Yes, yes. Of course. If they come back,
you may show them in.
有一位叫马丁太太的人
很有意思
Yes. You know, Mrs Martin,
it's very funny.
他们并不是我的朋友
还没见过我
They aren't exactly friends of mine.
They've never seen me.
-很奇怪是吧?
-的确很奇怪
- That's odd, isn't it?
- 'Tis odd, like you say.
既然我在这里
我就要见他们
And now that I'm here,
I'll have to meet them.
甚至要出去见他们
I may even go out and meet them.
但现在还不是时候
And then again, I may not. Not yet.
你继续睡吧
我把窗布拉下来
You go ahead with your nap.
I'll pull down the blind.
你们知道什麽?
你们只是在作势
What do you know?
You're bluffing. You've nothing on me.
邮局吗?
我要发一封电报...
Hello, Postal Union?
I want to send a telegram
给加州圣罗莎的
约瑟夫.牛顿
to Mrs Joseph Newton
in Santa Rosa, California.
下面是内容
准备好了吗?
Here's the message. Ready?
很想念你们句号
Lonesome for you all. Stop.
我就来找你们句号
Am coming out to stay
with you awhile. Stop.
周四到达
请来接我
Will arrive Thursday and try and stop me.
准确时间稍後告知
Will wire exact time later.
祝福所有人...
Love to you all...
并附上查利叔叔的吻
给小查莉
and a kiss for little Charlie
from her Uncle Charlie.
没错签名就是查利叔叔
That's right. That's the signature.
"Uncle Charlie. "
是的圣罗莎
That's right. Santa Rosa.
加州圣罗莎
Santa Rosa, California.
安妮听电话啊
Ann! Answer the telephone.
这里是牛顿家
Newton's residence.
Ann Newton speaking.
噢你好汉德森太太
我是安妮
Oh, hello, Mrs Henderson. This is Ann.
妈妈还没回家
Mother isn't home yet.
电报?我...
A telegram? Well...
我找不到铅笔
还是等她回来吧
I don't see a pencil, so maybe
she better call you back.
我正努力使自己
专注一些...
I'm trying to keep my mind free of things
that don't matter...
因为我在思考许多问题
because I have so much
to keep on my mind.
数不清的问题
Innumerable things.
我会告诉她回电的
谢谢你
I'll have her call back.
Thank you for calling.
再见
Goodbye.
安妮你妈妈呢?
Hello, Ann. Where's your mother?
-她出去了
-出去了?
- She ' s out.
- Out?
邮局的汉德森太太
刚刚打电话来的
Mrs Henderson just called
from the Postal Union Office.
她说我们收到一封电报
She says we have a telegram.
我本可以记下来的
但我找不到铅笔
I would have taken it down,
only I couldn't find a pencil. I looked.
电报吗?
Telegram, eh?
我说过你们的萨拉阿姨
如果领到执照就有麻烦了
I knew there'd be trouble if
your Aunt Sarah got her driver's licence.
-事故地点在哪里?
-我没有记下来
- Whereabouts was the accident?
- I didn't take notes.
噢那麽来一个吻好吗?
Oh. Then how about a kiss?
那不是很有趣吗?
我是家里最特别的女孩...
Isn't that the funniest thing?
Here I am, practically a child
看一些你们都不看的书
and I wouldn't read the things you read.
我想那些书
会给你带来恶梦的
Mm-hm. Well, I guess
they'd give you bad dreams.
恶梦?爸爸你不明白
那些传说和神话...
Bad dreams? You don't understand, Papa.
Mystery stories have done -
-罗杰呢?
-出去了还有人类的思想...
- Where's Roger?
- Out. The average mind -
-查莉呢?
-她在房间里思考
- Where's Charlie?
- Out. No, she's in her room thinking.
别看太多了
对你的眼睛不好
Well, don't read too much.
You'll ruin your eyes.
别看我的书了
你在看什麽?
And leave my book alone.
What's that you're reading?
-艾凡赫
-噢
- Ivanhoe.
- Hm? Oh.
-是谁?
-是我
- Who is it?
- It's me.
怎麽了?
不舒服吗?
What's the matter?
Don't you feel well?
不我很好
No. I'm perfectly well.
我已经想了很久
然後得出结论我应该放弃
I've just been thinking for hours,
and I've come to the conclusion I give up.
-只能放弃
-你要放弃什麽?
- I simply give up.
- What are you going to give up?
你认为家庭应该是
世界上最美好的事物吗?
Have you ever to thought that a family
should be the most wonderful thing ever?
而我们的家庭正趋向分解
And that this family's
just gone to pieces?
-是吗?
-当然是了
- We have?
- Of course we have.
我们只是惯例地生活下去
那种惯例太可怕了
We just sort of go along and
nothing happens. We're in a terrible rut.
几个月前我已经在想了
我们的将来会是怎样?
It's been on my mind for months.
What's going to be our future?
噢查莉别这样
事情不是那麽糟糕的
Oh, come now, Charlie.
Things aren't as bad as that.
-银行一月份已经
给我加薪了   -钱
- The bank gave me a raise last January.
- Money.
在我说心灵的时候
你怎麽可以说到钱呢?
How can you talk about money
when I'm talking about souls?
我们一起吃饭然後睡觉
We eat and sleep and that's about all.
并没有真正的交流
We don't even have
any real conversations.
我们只是说话
还有工作
- We just talk.
- And work.
可怜的妈妈
那麽辛苦地工作
Yes. Poor Mother. She works like a dog.
-就像一个佣人
-她在哪里?
- Just like a dog.
- Where is she?
她出去了
她回来了也是一样地工作
She's out. When she comes back,
it'll be the same thing.
做晚餐洗碗然後睡觉
我不明白她怎麽可以忍受
Dinner, then dishes, then bed.
I don't see how she stands it.
你知道她是一个很好的女人
You know,
she's really a wonderful woman.
她不仅仅是一个母亲
我们应该为她做些事情
I mean, she's not just a mother. And
I think we ought to do something for her.
-你觉得应该吗?
-应该那你认为要做些什麽呢?
- Don ' t you think we should?
- Yeah. What were you thinking of?
噢我想不出什麽
Oh, nothing, I suppose.
我想我们只能等待
奇迹出现了
I guess we'll just have to wait
for a miracle or something.
噢查莉你说得对
Oh, now, Charlie, you're right.
Absolutely right.
-我会想办法...
-噢我不再相信什麽好意愿了
- I'll figure out some way -
- I don't believe in good intentions now.
-我现在只是等待著奇迹
-噢查莉
- All I'm waiting for now is a miracle.
- Oh, Charlie.
後楼梯真陡啊
Those back stairs are steep.
怎麽了查莉?
怎麽了祖?
What's the matter, Charlie?
What's the matter, Joe?
-看来...
-噢我成了唠叨的老太婆了
- Well, it seems that, uh -
- Oh, I've become a nagging old maid.
这帽子你答应会扔掉的
但你还戴著它进城里
You went downtown in that awful old
hat you'd promised you'd throw away.
-妈妈
-亲爱的我戴什麽
帽子有什麽紧要吗?
- Mama.
- Darling, does it matter what hat I wear?
-妈妈
-妈妈你怎麽让
自己的孩子这样向你大喊呢?
- Mama.
- Why do you let that child yell at you?
-如果她...
-我反正都要下去的
- If she -
- I'm going downstairs, anyway.
祖我进来的时候
你们在谈什麽呢?
Joe, what were you
both talking about when I came in?
谈奇迹的事情
Something about a miracle.
没什麽的
查莉只是心情不太好
Oh, it's nothing.
Charlie ' s a bit under the weather.
她很快就会没事的
Oh. Well, she ' II be all right.
好了亲爱的快下去吧
不要站在这里
Well, come on, dear. Let's go
downstairs. No use standing here.
我去喝一瓶啤酒
I'm going to get myself a bottle of beer.
妈妈
我要去发一封电报
Mother, I'm going downtown
and send a telegram.
为什麽
你要发电报给谁?
Why, darling, who do you know
to send a telegram to?
我知道谁可以来拯救我们
I know a wonderful person who'll come
and stir us up. Just the one to save us.
拯救我们?
What do you mean, "save us"?
现在就只有一个人可以做到
All this time, there's been
one right person to save us.
-妈妈查理叔叔的地址是什麽?
-查理叔叔?
- What's Uncle Charlie's address?
- Uncle Charlie?
-你不是去问他要钱吧?
-当然不是了
- You're not going to ask him for money?
- Of course not.
那对我们没帮助地址呢?
上次我放在...
That wouldn't help us.
What's his address?
你们知道从药房那里...
- The last address I had -
- Do you know how many steps it is
走回家要走多少步呢?
to get from here
to the drugstore and back?
- 649.
-如果你忘记了, 我就不告诉你
- If you've forgotten, I won't tell you.
-我记起来了是费城
- I remember. Philadelphia.
-你不能无缘无故地叫一个大忙人过来啊
You can't ask a busy man
to come all this way for nothing.
他会来的, 我的名字是因他而起的
He'll come for me. I'm named after him.
此外, 我们是他唯一的亲戚
Besides, we're the only relatives
he has in the world.
如果从第四街走回来, 就是802步
If you come all the way up Fourth Street, it's 802.
-妈妈你猜猜?
-我没时间去猜
- Mama, guess what?
- I have no time for guessing.
你头发上面的是什麽?
What's that thing in your hair?
我要告诉你的
要猜的话有趣一点
Well, I'll tell you anyway, even though
I think it's nicer when people guess.
汉德森太太叫你打电话
给邮局我们有一封电报
Mrs Henderson said to call her at
the telegraph office. We have a telegram.
安妮你不应该
把东西放在耳朵後面的
Ann, I don't think you ought to put things
behind your ears.
-会进耳朵里面的
-艾玛安妮说我们有电报
- Something might get into your ear.
- Emmy, Ann says we have a telegram.
我想你应该去查清楚
可能有人病了
I think you ought to find out about it.
Somebody might be sick or something.
-汉德森太太没有读出来...
因为我找不到铅笔
Mrs Henderson didn't read the telegram
because I couldn't find a pencil.
等我有了屋子之後
我会在周围放满铅笔
When I have a house, it's going
to be full of well-sharpened pencils.
-汉德森太太有说是哪里来的电报吗?
-没有
- Did Mrs Henderson say who it's from?
- No, she didn't.
她应该说电报从哪里来的
She might have said who it was from.
-安妮那是我的椅子啊
-我会问清楚的
Come on, Ann. That's my chair.
I'll call up and find out.
你们静一会好吗
If you will be quiet just a second.
你好请接181好吗?
Hello. 181, please. I wonder who it can be?
没什麽就是181
Oh, nothing, Operator. Just 181.
-如果是我姐姐的...
-喂?
- If that's from my sister -
- Hello?
汉德森太太吗?
我是艾玛
Mrs Henderson? This is Emma Newton.
安妮说我有一封电报
Ann says you have a telegram for me.
妈妈你不用那麽大声的
- Mama, you don't have to shout.
- Ssh.
爸爸妈妈
好像没用过电话一样
Really, Papa. You'd think
Mama had never seen a phone.
她这样很不科学
She makes no allowance for science.
认为用声音
就可以压倒听众
She thinks she has to cover the distance
by sheer lungpower.
真好啊是周四吗?
Why, how wonderful. Thursday, you say?
似乎有人就要来了
Looks like somebody's coming.
-谁要来啊妈妈?
-那真是最大的惊喜啊
- Who's coming, Ma?
- Well, it's the most wonderful surprise.
是我的弟弟就是他
It's my brother, you know.
My younger brother. The baby.
是啊他被宠坏了家里
最小的一个总会被宠坏的
Yes, of course, a little spoiled.
Families always spoil the youngest.
这真是太好了
Well, it's just simply wonderful.
谢谢你汉德森太太
Thanks most awfully, Mrs Henderson.
好了
Well...
你猜是谁?
查理就要来了
What do you think? Charles is coming.
-谁?
-你们的查理叔叔
- Who?
- Your Uncle Charlie.
-查理叔叔?
Did you say "Charles"?
-我们的查莉正去给他发电报呢
-她为什麽那样做呢?
And our Charlie's sending him a telegram.
Now, what made her think to do that?
你好啊查莉
你妈妈刚打电话来了
Hello, Charlie. I just called your house.
-你妈妈的电报
-是吗?
- Telegram for your mother.
- Did you?
本来让比尔送过去的
你现在可以拿走了
Gonna send that by Bill Forest,
but you can take it.
-谢谢
-是你叔叔的
Thanks. From your uncle.
The spoiled one.
我叔叔?
查理叔叔?
My uncle? My Uncle Charlie?
是的
Yeah.
汉德森太太
你相信心灵感应吗?
Mrs Henderson,
do you believe in telepathy?
噢那是我的工作啊
Well, I ought to. That's my business.
不是邮件
是心灵感应啊
Oh, not telegraphy. Mental telepathy.
那就是说...
你想到了一些事情
Like...
well, suppose you have a thought,
假设你想到了一个
和你很相似的人
and suppose the thought's about
someone you're in tune with.
然後那个与你
相隔千里的人回应你
Then across miles, that person knows
what you're thinking and answers you.
-就是心灵感应
-我不知道你在说什麽
- And it's all mental.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
我只会收发邮件
I only send telegrams the normal way.
他听见我的
He heard me. He heard me.
-奥提斯先生?
-什麽?
- Mr Otis? Mr Otis?
- Yes?
就到圣罗莎了
你应该准备一下
You're almost in Santa Rosa. Want to be
ready when you get into Santa Rosa.
-我准备好了谢谢
-那我帮你拿行李出来
- I'm ready now. Thanks.
- Then I'll get all your bags out for you.
-你觉得怎麽了
奥提斯先生?-很好
- How you feelin', Mr Otis?
- Pretty well.
只是有点虚弱
其他都很好
A little weak
but pretty well on the whole.
哦
Mm-hm.
哈里告诉他你是医生吧
Harry, tell the porter you're a doctor.
看看他有什麽问题
你也许可以帮他的
Ask if there's anything you can do.
Maybe you can help that poor soul.
我正在休假啊搬运工
我丈夫是医生你去问问他...
- I'm on my vacation.
- My husband's a doctor and if there's -
不必了夫人
他不想见任何人
No, Ma'am. He's a very sick man.
Won't see anyone.
我们上车之後就没见他出来
I haven't set eyes on him myself
since we first got on the train.
你脸色也不太好啊
Well, you don ' t look very well either.
到了孩子们出来吧
Ah, here we are. Come on, children.
把门关好对了
Close the door, there. That's right.
-你就是...
-查理
- Oh, are you -
- Charlie. Young Charlie.
小查莉我开始
还认不出来呢我以为你病了
At first, I didn't know you.
I thought you were sick.
-病了?
-你没病的
- Sick?
- You aren't sick, are you?
爸爸他在这里!
Look, Pop! Here he is!
查理叔叔你没病啊
真有点奇怪
Why, Uncle Charlie, you're not sick.
That was the funniest thing.
-我病了?祖你好啊
-你好查理
- Me, sick? Well, Joe, how are you?
- Alright, Charles.
你们好啊罗杰安妮
应该认不出我了
Roger. Hello, Ann.
I bet you don't remember me.
我隐约记起
你样子好像不同了
I remember you sort of.
You look different.
我们赶快回去吧
艾玛就做好晚餐了
Well, we better get started.
Emma's got the dinner almost ready.
她不能来车站
晚餐第一啊
I couldn't persuade her to come
to the station. Dinner came first.
-罗杰拿行李我来吧查理
-谢谢祖
- Roger, get the bags. I'll take that.
- Thank you, Joe.
到了来吧
That's it. Come on. Let's go.
罗杰
拿这些行李
Come on, Roger, get these bags.
噢对你来说真的不重吗?
You, uh, sure that isn't
too heavy for you?
没什麽
我喜欢搬东西的
Oh, no. It's nothing. I love to carry.
艾玛别动
Emma. Don't move.
站在那里
你不像是艾玛.牛顿
Standing there,
you don't look like Emma Newton.
你还是艾玛.奥克里
住在明尼苏达州
圣保罗市本翰大街46号
You look like Emma Spencer Oakley of
46 Burnham Street, St Paul, Minnesota.
-那一区最漂亮的女孩!
-查理
- The prettiest girl on the block.
- Charles.
查莉妈妈车站里
只有叔叔一个人下车
Mama, nobody got off the train
but Uncle Charlie.
-让我看看你
-只有我们在那里接人
- Let me look at you.
- There was only us meeting somebody.
很难想像你会来这里
- To think you could take the time off.
- There was only one bed made up.
-噢查理你来了真好
-艾玛别哭啊
- It's so wonderful to have you here.
- Emmy, Emmy, don't cry.
你在想起
本翰大街46号吧
And imagine your thinking
of 46 Burnham Street.
我很多年没想过那里了
I haven't thought of that
funny old street in years.
我一直想起过去那些
美好的事情艾玛他样子怎麽了?
I keep remembering those things.
All the old things.
还是没变对吧?
Emmy, how's he look?
Same old Charles, eh?
罗杰安妮
去拿那些包
Roger, Ann, get these other bags.
你就住在查莉的房间里
You have Charlie's room
right here at the head of the stairs.
艾玛本想安妮搬出来的
但查理说你在这里会舒服些
Emmy wanted to move Ann, but Charlie
thought you'd be more comfortable here.
来吧罗杰
Come on, Roger.
-别把帽子放在床上啊
-你也迷信吗祖?
- Ah-ah! Don't put the hat on the bed.
- Superstitious, Joe?
不但我不想
带来什麽麻烦事
No, but I don't believe in inviting trouble.
那游艇并不是最大的
但在图书馆里有壁炉...
It wasn't the biggest yacht in the world,
but it had a fireplace in the library
酒吧的面板都是桃木做的
and the bar was panelled
in bleached mahogany.
只要按那个键...好了
不说我的
You pushed a button and...
What am I talking about? That's all over.
说说你们吧
Let's talk about you.
查莉这是我见你
穿过的最漂亮的裙子啊
Charlie,
that's the prettiest dress I ever saw.
我也这样认为啊
I think so, too.
查理你忘记了吗?
Why, Charles, don't you remember?
忘记?忘记什麽?
Remember? Remember what?
查理叔叔
这是你寄给我的是吗?
- Why, Uncle Charlie, you sent it to me.
- I did?
是啊看我
总是忘了一些事情
Well, say, I've been sitting here
all this time forgetting something.
安妮罗杰
Ann. Roger.
-看看你们
-祖不知道你有没有
- Look at that. Oh, dear now.
- Joe. Don't know whether you had one.
不用给我买礼物吧
给孩子们就可以了
You didn't have to think of me, Charles.
Presents for the children are alright.
噢...我还没有过
一苹腕表呢
Say... I've never had a wristwatch.
银行里的同事
还说我是运动型呢
Fellows at the bank'll think
I'm quite a sport.
艾玛你有两份
一新一旧
I have two for you, Emmy.
One old and one new.
噢查理
是什麽呢?
Oh, Charles. What is it?
你真是...
- You shouldn't have. Really. No.
- Well, yeah.
噢查理
Oh, Charles.
多麽漂亮啊
Oh, how... beautiful.
我总想有一件的
Oh, I've-I've always wanted one.
是啊妈妈
你应该有一件的
Oh, Mother, it's exactly right.
It's what you should have.
看看
Look, Emmy.
查理你一直带在身边
Charles. You've had these all along.
是啊艾玛很多年了
Mm-hm. All along, Emmy.
All these years.
无论去哪里
都存放在保险箱
Safe in a deposit box,
no matter where I was.
噢是外公和外婆吗?
Oh. Grandpa and Grandma?
1888年
1888.
53年前了
53 years ago.
-他们很和蔼对吗?
-噢她很美啊
Aren't they sweet?
My, she was pretty.
在那个时候
每个人都很美的
Everybody was sweet and pretty then.
The whole world.
一个精彩的世界
不像现在的那样
A wonderful world.
Not like the world today.
不像现在的世界
Not like the world now.
那时候年轻真好
It was great to be young then.
我们现在很开心啊
看看大家
We're all happy now, Uncle Charlie.
Look at us.
-我们第一次同时那麽开心
-现在是你的礼物了查莉
- And we're all happy at the same time.
- Now, for your present, Charlie.
噢我什麽都不需要
现在已经很满足了
Oh, I don't want anything.
Right now, I have enough.
你来之前
我以为我需要很多东西
Before you came,
I didn't think I had anything,
但现在我觉得不需要了
but now I don't want another thing.
-她傻了
-她并不是傻了
- She's crazy.
- She doesn't mean it.
她其实是在假装
像小说里面的女孩那样
If you ask me, I think she's putting on,
like girls in books.
口里说不需要
而後来就什麽都想要
The ones that say they don't want
anything always get more in the end.
-她是这样想的
-她不傻啊
- That's what she's hoping.
- She's not crazy.
在班里她是最聪明的
The smartest girl
in her class at school.
-独自一人在辩论赛中赢了里奇门中学辩论队
-她很有头脑的
Won the debate against theEast
Richmond HighSchool. She's got brains.
我是认真的
不必给我任何东西
I meant it.
Please don't give me anything.
-为什麽?
-我不知道怎麽解释
- Nothing?
- Oh, I can't explain it.
你来了之後
妈妈很开心...
But you came here
and Mother's so happy and...
噢我很高兴我们名字一样
Oh, I'm glad that she named me after you
and that she thinks we're both alike.
我想我们是相同的
I think we are, too. I know it.
你送我东西的话
会破坏事情的
Oh, it would spoil things
if you should give me anything.
你真是个奇怪的女孩
那会破坏什麽事呢?
You're a strange girl, Charlie.
Why would it spoil things?
因为我们并不仅
是叔叔和外甥女关系
Because we're not just an uncle
and a niece. It's something else.
我了解你
别人了解你不多
I know you. I know that you don't
tell people a lot of things.
我觉得在你身上有些事情...
I don't either. I have a feeling
that inside you somewhere,
没有其他任何人知道
there's something nobody knows about.
没有人知道?
Something... nobody knows?
是一些很惊奇的事情
我会知道的
Something secret and wonderful and...
I'll find it out.
知道太多并不好啊查莉
It's not good
to find out too much, Charlie.
我们就像双胞胎
不是吗?
But we're sort of like twins.
Don't you see?
-我们都知道的
-把手给我查莉
- We have to know.
- Give me your hand, Charlie.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-你不看一眼啊
-我不需要看了
- You didn't even look at it.
- I don't have to.
你送我什麽都是一样的
No matter what you gave me,
it'd be the same.
让我给你看看吧
Here. Let me show you.
这是一颗绿宝石
很漂亮的
It's a good emerald. A really good one.
绿宝石是世上
最美丽的东西
Good emeralds are
the most beautiful things in the world.
-你刻了一些字在上面
-没有啊如果你要我帮你拿去刻
- You've had something engraved.
- I haven't, but I will if you like it.
有的查理叔叔
不过有点模糊
Yes, you have, Uncle Charlie.
It's very faint.
B.M赠予T.S
"T.S. From B.M."
像是人名的缩写啊
But... Why, it must be someone's initials.
那麽我是给珠宝商骗了
Well, I've been rooked.
The jeweller rooked me.
-噢没所谓的
-先还我吧我叫人把字去掉
- Oh, it doesn't matter. Really.
- Give it back. I'll have it taken off.
不我喜欢
No, No. I like it this way.
其他人可能会
很喜欢这个的
Someone else was probably happy
with this ring.
噢真的很美
Oh, it's perfect the way it is.
你端咖啡吧
You bring the coffee.
在餐桌上唱歌
会嫁一个呆丈夫的
Sing at the table,
you'll marry a crazy husband.
迷信已被证明
是绝对错误的
Superstitions have been
proved 100% wrong.
对了我想把一些钱
转来这里
Yes, I've been thinking of transferring
some money out here from the East.
在我有计划前
先存在你们银行里祖
I could put it in your bank, Joe,
until I found out what's what.
我想你们银行
可以存钱的吧?
Uh, I suppose your bank
does take money, huh?
那是我们的一项
赚快钱的业务啊
That's one thing we do.
Rake in the dough.
但不保证可以拿回来
Can't promise to give it back.
我明天早\'上
就去开一个户口
Well, I'll go downtown in the morning
and open an account.
-4万美金应该够了吧?
-那是很大的一笔钱啊
- 30 or 40,000 just to start things off?
- That's a lot of money.
他不会保留很久的
政府会拿走他的钱
He won't have it long.
The government will get it.
-政府只会...
-不要说些反政府的话啊罗杰
- The government gets -
- Don't talk against the government.
天啊
The way men do things.
我的脑子里总是出现那首曲
I can't get that tune out of my head.
可能有人告诉过我
但我忘记了
Maybe if somebody tells me what it is,
I'll forget it.
-是一首华尔兹
-我知道但是哪一首呢?
- It's a waltz.
- I know it is, but what one?
真的很奇怪
You know, it's the funniest thing.
我脑子里总是
出现那首曲...
Sometimes I get a tune
in my head like that
不久我好像听到有人也在哼
and pretty soon, I hear
somebody else humming it too.
我想那首曲一定
在大脑里传来传去
I think tunes jump from head to head.
你知道那是什麽吗
查理叔叔?
Do you know whatit is,
Uncle Charlie?
不我不知道
Uh, no. No. I-I-I don't know what it is.
让我想想...
I remember.
Uh... It's on the tip of my tongue.
应该是维克托.贺伯特
It's a waltz and it's Victor Herbert.
-维克托.贺伯特不是华尔兹啊
-应该是蓝色多瑙河吧
- Victor Herbert wasn't a waltz.
- It's the Blue Danube Waltz.
噢是啊
Oh, yes. Of course it is.
不不是的查理叔叔
我知道了是快乐...
No, it isn't, Uncle Charlie.
I know what it is. It's the Merry -
对不起搞得一团糟
- I'm terribly sorry, Emmy.
- Nothing to make a fuss about.
查理我们洗碗的时候
你去客厅那里...
Charles, while we do the dishes,
why don't you come in the living room
坐在沙发上看看报纸吧
and stretch out on the sofa
and read the evening paper?
你也帮不了什麽
You never were much on helping.
-祖贺博来了
-安妮罗杰来帮我
- Joe, here's Herbert.
- Ann, Roger, help me here.
贺博是祖的朋友
他们是评论家
Herbert's a friend of Joe's.
They're literary critics.
你好啊贺博
吃过晚饭了吗?
Hello, Herb. Had your supper?
-一小时前就吃了
-是吗?
- Had mine an hour ago.
- Hour ago, huh?
-噢手表
-是礼物
- Oh. A watch.
- Yeah, a present.
贺博这位是我内弟
Here, Herb.
I'd like you to meet my brother-in-law.
-查理这位是贺博
-你好贺博
- Charles, this is Herb Hawkins.
- Nice to know you, Mr Hawkins.
-谢谢
-贺博你母亲还好吗?
- Fine, thank you.
- How's your mother, Herb?
噢还在恢复
- Oh, uh, just middling.
- Uh-huh.
不好意思贺博
- Excuse me, Herb.
- Oh.
-噢
-你妈妈的事我很难过
Thank you.
I'm sorry your mother's not better.
-谢谢你
-谢谢
- Thank you, dear. There, now.
- Thank you.
过一种清闲的生活吧
Lead a life of luxury.
我要去看查莉在做什麽
Well, I must go and see
what Charlie ' s doing.
我内弟从东部来
纽约人
Wife's brother from the East.
New York man.
对孩子们好啊
明白我的意思吗?
Good for the children.
You know what I mean?
在生意上?
他可是一个很出众的人
In business?
Well, he takes himself very seriously.
你的事怎麽了?
Well, how's everything?
你看过这本书吗?
Say, ha-have you read this one? Huh?
那个法国人把难题都解决了
That little Frenchman beats them all.
就像福尔摩斯那样
You can talk all you like
about Sherlock Holmes.
那个法国人把难题都解决了
That little Frenchman beats 'em all.
我看过了
但注射气泡未必可以致命
I read it. Air bubbles don't
necessarily kill a person.
那些作家想像力太丰富了
Those writers from the other side
get too fancy.
-谋杀的最好方法就是...
-我知道我知道
- The best way to commit a murder-
- I know, I know.
用硬器打击头的後部
Hit 'em on the head
with a blunt instrument.
对极了不是吗?听著
Well, it's true, isn't it? Listen.
如果我想明天谋杀你
If I wanted to murder you tomorrow,
我还会浪费时间
去给你做皮下注射吗?
do you think
I'd waste my time on fancy hypodermics?
-或者是伊尼?
-那是什麽?
- Or on Inee?
- What's that?
伊尼是一种
印度毒箭上的毒药   哦
- Inee. Indian arrow poison.
- Oh.
如果我发现你一个人走著
Listen,
I'd find out if you were alone, walk in,
我就用铁管给你的头几下
hit you on the head with a piece
of lead pipe or a loaded cane -
那有什麽意思?
What'd be the fun of that?
你的计划呢?
你的线索呢?
Where's your planning?
Where's your clues?
我不想有什麽线索
我只想谋杀你
I don't want any clues.
I want to murder you.
我要线索来做什麽?
What do I want with clues?
如果没有线索那怎麽成书?
Well, if you haven't got any clues,
where's your book?
我不是在说写书
我说的是要谋杀你!
I'm not talkin' 'bout writing books.
I'm talking about killing you!
如果我要谋杀你的话
我才不会用那些笨重的工具
If I was going to kill you, I wouldn't do
a dumb thing like hitting you on the head.
首先
我不想被人找到指纹
First of all,
I don't like the fingerprint angle.
我会戴手套
将你的手按在那铁管上...
Of course, I could always wear gloves,
press your hands against the pipe
造成是你自杀的情形,噢!
after you were dead
and make you look like a suicide.
但那是很难让人相信你是自杀的
所以我要谋杀你而不被看出是谋杀
But you wouldn't beat yourself to death.
I'd do it so it didn't look like murder.
-安妮?
Oh, Ann?
-什麽?
-来这里
- What?
- Come here.
你见过怎样用报纸
做一间房子吗?
Did you ever see a house
made out of newspapers?
看好了
Well, watch.
先拿一张报纸出来
You-You take one sheet here.
然後在这里撕开
OK? And you tear it down here.
那里也撕开
And you tear it there.
然後从两边折起来
You fold it over here at the side.
叠在一起
Fold over the other side here.
这样竖起来
And turn it up there.
然後门口...
Now with... the door...
就是这里了
Right off... and there.
我已经不是小孩了
而且这是爸爸的报纸
I'm not a baby any more.
Besides, that's Papa's paper.
罗杰看看这是什麽
一间可爱的小棚子
Oh, Roger, look what
we ' ve got. A nice, little red barn.
-那是爸爸的报纸啊
-没什麽的
- You've got Papa's paper.
- Oh, that's alright.
再摊开就没事了
-没人会看出来的
Simply unfold it.
Nobody will ever know the difference.
-你们在做什麽?
What are you two doing?
-你们都知道那是爸爸的报纸
-噢查莉是我的错, 我在玩个小游戏
- You know that's father's paper.
- It's my fault. I was playing a game.
-不知道那是你爸爸的报纸
-噢没什麽
- Didn't think about it as Joe's pap.
- Oh, that's alright.
第一页第五页
第八页...
Here's page one, five... eight.
-第三和第四页在哪里?
-我们没碰过啊
- What did you do with three and four?
- We never touched it.
只有查理叔叔碰过
Really. Uncle Charlie ' s
the only one that touched it.
应该没什麽的
Oh, well. I guess it's all right.
放整齐一点
爸爸可能看不出来
If I fold it very neatly,
maybe he won ' t notice.
请进
Come in.
-我给你拿了些水
I brought you water.
-谢谢你
Oh, thank you, Charlie.
That's very thoughtful of you.
祝你好梦
Pleasant dreams.
-查理叔叔
Uncle Charlie...
我知道了一些你以为我不知道的秘密
什麽秘密?
- I know a secret you don't think I know.
- What secret?
记得我说过不要隐藏什麽
因为我会发现的吗?
Remember I said you couldn't hide
anything from me because I'd find it out?
现在我知道今晚的报纸
和你是有关系的
Well, now I know there was something
in the evening paper about you.
-和我有关?
-是的
About me in the evening paper?
所以你才和
安妮和罗杰玩那游戏
And that's why you played that game
with Ann and Roger.
你不想我们知道
并把报纸撕掉了
You didn't want us to know
and you wanted to tear the paper.
我想你应该告诉我吧
Now I know. You might as well tell me.
被你捉到了查莉
Well, you've got me there, Charlie.
并不完全和我有关只是...
Only it wasn't about me.
It was about, uh...
我以前认识的某人
someone I used to know.
看看!
There!
那不关你的事!
It's none of your business.
噢查理叔叔
你弄痛我了
Oh! Uncle Charlie, you're hurting me.
噢查莉你的手
- Oh, Charlie.
- Your hands.
查莉我无意弄痛你的
Charlie, I didn't mean to hurt you.
我是玩著的
I was just fooling.
那只是...一些流言
It was nothing. Just... Just some gossip.
是我以前的朋友的绯闻
Not very pretty,
about someone I once met up with.
不适合你们看的
Not for you to read.
忘记它吧
Forget it.
-晚安小查莉
-晚安查理叔叔好梦
- Good night, young Charlie.
- Good night. Pleasant dreams.
-查理叔叔会逗留多久?
-他不走就好了
- How long is Uncle Charlie staying?
- Forever, I hope.
他自己没有屋子吗?
Hasn't he got a house of his own?
既然你现在来这里了
我希望...
Not that I mind you in here,
可以保留一点隐私
but I never can tell
when I'll want some privacy.
你还是睡觉吧小宝贝
You better go to sleep, baby.
-祈祷了吗?
-我忘记了
- You said your prayers?
- I forgot.
还是祈祷吧
You better say them.
我即将睡觉
希望上帝...
I lay me down to sleep,
I pray the Lord my soul to keep -
-别说太说很晚了
-带走我的心灵
- Don't bless too many people. It's late.
- I pray the Lord my soul to take.
愿上帝保佑我妈妈爸爸
还有总统...
God bless Mama, Papa, Captain Midnight,
Veronica Lake and the president -
-亲爱的你这样说没完没了啊
-还有查理叔叔阿门
- You can't say them all tonight, dear.
- Oh, and Uncle Charlie. Amen.
-准备好吃早\'餐了吗?
-噢是咖啡啊艾玛
- All ready for breakfast?
- Oh, coffee, Emmy.
我不知道你怎麽会
喜欢在床上吃东西
I don't know how you do it.
Now, I'm never comfortable eating in bed.
孩子们回来之後
我有时也会在床上吃...
I had to have my meals in bed for a while
但我不喜欢那样
after the children came,
but I never liked it.
早\'上我不知道该做什麽好
说话前也要先喝一杯咖啡
I can't face the world in the morning.
I must have coffee before I can speak.
我不介意纵容你一下
Well, I don't mind pampering you
your first morning,
但我想你在镇是唯一
在十点半吃早\'餐的人了
but I think you're the only person
in this town to have breakfast at 10:30.
你还在睡的时候
报社的人说想来做个访问
And while you were sleeping,
the newspaper called up for an interview.
访问我?
With me?
我参加的那个妇女
俱乐部希望你去做一次演讲
And the women's club I belong to
wants you to give a little talk.
妇女俱乐部
Women's club.
噢你还没把东西放好啊
我帮你吧
Oh! Oh, you haven't finished unpacking.
I'll do that for you.
-查莉去哪里了?
-她在屋子里团团转像傻了一样
- Where ' s Charlie?
- She's running around like a mad thing.
她觉得什麽都需要修理一下
She thinks everything needs fixing.
我告诉你
你可不是这里唯一的名人
But what I wanted to tell you was that
you're not the only celebrity in this town.
牛顿一家都成为了镇里的
关注焦点你想说什麽?
- We're all going to be in limelight.
- What are you cooking up?
今天早\'上来的那个
叫格翰的年轻人...
Well, a young man called this morning,
said his name was Graham,
想采访我们家里的
and he wants to interview
everybody in this house.
-采访所有人?
-他是那样说的
- Interview everybody?
- That's what he said.
他说是什麽委员会派他来...
He's being sent around the country
by some kind of institute or committee
挑选有代表性的
美国家庭来访问
and he has to pick a representative
American family and ask them questions.
像是一种调查
国家公众调查
It's a kind of a poll.
It's called the National Public Survey.
为什麽他要选这个家庭呢?
Wonder how he happened
to pick this family?
他说要挑选有
代表性的美国家庭
Well, he said he wanted
a typical American family.
我告诉他我们不是的
I told him
we weren't a typical American family.
如果他们问我的事情
我就不会回答他们
If he's going to ask a lot of questions,
he can leave me out of it.
噢你的事情
我们也说不详细啊
Oh, but you could tell him so much more
than any of us could.
-他说还要拍照片
-拍照片
- He's going to take our pictures too.
- Pictures.
噢多麽漂亮啊
My, isn't that lovely?
他们两个都是很年轻的
You see, there were really,
there were two young men.
一个负责拍照
One of them takes the pictures.
-噢还有两个人啊
-是的格翰先生为人好一点
- Oh, there were two.
- Yes. Mr Graham was the nicest.
他说我们不必打扮的
Oh, he doesn't want us
to dress up or anything.
-他就想我们像往常一样
He just wants us to act
the way we always do.
-艾玛女人都是很笨的
-她们总会坏事
Emmy, women are fools.
They'd fall for anything.
为什麽你会让
两个陌生人进屋里捣乱?
Why do you let two strangers come
and turn this place upside down.
哪个家庭会欢迎
那些窥探者呢?
Why expose the family
to a couple of snoopers?
-你应该警觉一点
-查理我只是...
- You should have more sense.
- Why, Charles, I -
-早\'安查理叔叔
-早\'安查莉
- Good morning, Uncle Charlie.
- Good morning, Charlie.
你妈妈说牛顿家
被一些小毛孩选中了
Your mother says the Newtons have been
picked for all-American suckers.
-你怎麽认为?
-他们来的时候查莉不在
- What do you know about it?
- Charlie wasn't here when they came.
但是格翰先生的行为...
一点也不像是窥探
But really, the way Mr Graham told it,
it wasn't like snooping at all.
那是公民的责任
是政府的需要
It was our duty as citizens.
It's something the government wants.
政府?可能不太准确
但那是为了公众利益
- Government?
- Well, it's for the public good.
当我告诉他们你曾去过
哪些地方时他们很感兴趣
I told them about you andtheplaces
you've been and he was very interested.
艾玛我与此事是无关的
Now, listen, Emmy.
I'll have nothing to do with this.
我只是来探望你们
我建议你请他们吃闭\'门羹吧
I'm just a visitor here and my advice
to you is to slam the door in his face.
噢我不能这样做啊
Oh. Well, I-I couldn't do that.
如果你不想的话
可以不见他们的
But you don't have to meet him
if you don't want to.
我觉得那很有意思啊
Well, I think I'd be kind of exciting.
他拿你的照片
也没什麽作用啊
He'd take your photograph
and then we could have it for nothing.
不了我这一生都没拍过照
我也不想拍照
No thank you. I've never been
photographed and I don't want to be.
噢查理
你怎麽可以这样说呢?
Oh, Charles, how can you talk that way?
我有你的照片
给查莉保管著
I had a photograph of you.
I gave it to Charlie.
-我说过没有啊
-我想你忘记了
I tell you, there are none.
I guess you've forgotten this one.
去拿吧查莉
Get it, Charlie.
你真的记不起来吗?
You sure you don't remember?
被人拍下来的我
当然记不起来
Of course I don't
ever remember being photographed.
本翰大街46号
46 Burnham Street.
那自行车是你的圣诞礼物
Mm-hm. It was taken
the Christmas you got your bicycle.
-那时就在你出意外之前
-查理叔叔你很可爱啊
- Just before your accident.
- Uncle Charlie, you were beautiful.
是吧?他那时很文静
喜欢读书
Wasn't he, though?
And such a quiet boy. Always reading.
爸爸不应该给你买那自行车的
你不懂怎麽骑
Papa shouldn't have got you that bicycle.
You didn't know how to handle it.
他在冰滑的路上骑车
并撞到了电车
He took it right out on the icy road
and skidded into a streetcar.
我们以为他不行了
幸好他没事
- We thought he was going to die.
- I'm glad he didn't.
那真的很险头骨也裂了
躺了很久
He almost did. He fractured his skull,
and he was laid up so long.
然後他慢慢康复了
And then, when he was getting well,
there was no holding him.
之後的事情对他来说
似乎太不足够了...
And it was just as though
all the rest he had was too much for him
他开始变得淘气起来
and he had to get into mischief
to blow off steam.
那事之後
他再也没怎麽读书了
He didn't do much reading after that,
let me tell you.
他在意外养伤的时候
就已经读够了
It was taken the very day
he had his accident.
不久之後这张照片拿了回家
妈妈哭得很厉害
A few days later when the pictures
came home, how mama cried.
担心他的样子
和为人会不会变了
She wondered if he'd ever look the same.
She wondered if he'd ever be the same.
回顾过去有什麽用?
展望未来又有什麽用?
What's the use of looking backward?
What's the use of looking ahead?
今天才是关键
那就是我的哲学今天
Today's the thing.
That's my philosophy. Today.
如果这样那你就
应该快点把早\'餐吃完...
If today's the thing,
then you'd better finish your breakfast
然後赶快去银行
祖在等你呢
and get down to the bank
because Joe'll be waiting.
查莉你不要迟到啊
做调查的人四点就来了
Charlie, don't be late back.
The survey men are coming at 4:00.
-你好查莉
-你好梅芝
- Good morning, Charlie.
- Hello, Madge.
-你好查莉
-你好卡芙琳
- Good morning, Charlie.
- Hello, Catherine.
看到她们怎麽看你的吗?
一定很想知道你是谁
Did you see the way they looked at you?
I bet they wonder who you are.
噢查理叔叔我想和你说话
大家都在看著我
Uncle Charlie, I love to walk with you.
I want everybody to see you.
爸爸就在那个窗口
There's Papa in that window over there.
祖挪用公款的事
晚些再忙好吗?
Hello, Joe. Can you stop embezzling
a minute and give me your attention?
噢...
Oh, uh...
查理我们在这里
不开那种玩笑的
Charles, we don't joke
about such things here.
噢那在月底总数的
不足是什麽?
Oh, what's a little shortage in the books
at the end of the month?
一个好的银行职员
知道该怎麽做的对吗查莉?
Any good bank clerk can cover up
alittle shortage. Isn't that right, Charlie
-大家都听到了
-那就好大家都知道这里是银行
- Everyone can hear you.
- Good. We all know what banks are.
看上去很正常但在内里
就不知道有什麽发生了
Look all right, but noone knows
what goes on when they lock the doors.
但骗不了我祖
带我去见你们的经理吧
Can't fool me, though.
Well, Joe, let's see your president.
-你还要开个户口吗查理?
-我就为此而来啊
Still want to open that account, Charles?
That's why I'm here.
那你在这里先等一下
我去找格林先生
Well, uh, you wait right here.
I'll see if Mr Greene's busy.
查理他不喜欢
开那种玩笑的
And, uh, Charles, he doesn't care much
for jokes about banks.
我想四万美金对他来说
肯定不是玩笑了吧
Well, $40,000 is no joke.
Not to him, I bet.
那是我的一个玩笑
这个世界都在拿我开玩笑
It's a joke to me.
The whole world's a joke to me.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
你不应该那样逗我爸爸
You shouldn't tease Papa like that.
我不是要逗他
我只是不喜欢这里的气氛
I wasn't teasing him.
I just hate this stuffy atmosphere.
他叫我们进去啊
They're waving for us to come in.
-你好格林先生
-你好查莉
- Hello, Mr Greene.
- Hello, Charlie.
格林先生这位是我内弟
奥克里先生
Well, Mr Greene, this is
my brother-in-law, Mr Oakley.
-你好
-你好奥克里先生
- How do you do?
- How are you, Mr Oakley?
格林先生我打算
在这里逗留一段时间
Well, Mr Greene, I was thinking
of settling down here for a while.
-强大的国家
Great country. Great country.
-当然你最近在干什麽?
We think so. What have you been doing?
为这里做点贡献
I suppose you might call me a promoter.
I've done a little bit of everything.
问题是当我赚到钱
我就对钱没有了兴趣
The only trouble is that once I make
the money, I'm not interested in it.
对钱没有了兴趣?
Not interested in money?
外面有很多钱
在等著有人去捡啊
You know there's money just lying around
waiting for somebody to pick it up.
我想我应该
把一些零钱存起来
I thought maybe I'd put some of
my loose cash away for safekeeping.
很自然我就想到了祖工作的
银行零钱?
- In the bank where Joe works, naturally.
- Loose cash?
我有个习惯在旅行的时候
带著大量的现金
Well, I got in a habit of carrying a lot
of cash with me when I was travelling.
-是个危险的习惯啊奥克里先生
-我还没丢过一分钱呢格林先生
- A dangerous habit.
- Never lost a penny in my life.
我想上天是
保佑那些蠢人和恶棍的
I guess heaven takes care
of fools and scoundrels.
-是啊
-三万三万五四万
- Yes.
- Thirty, thirty-five...
四万开个户口好吗?
Forty thousand.
Shall we start with forty?
只要填一张资料纸就可以了
奥克里先生细节的问题
- If you'll just write out a deposit slip.
- Ah, details.
你遇到我这样注意
细节的人就对了格林先生
I'm glad to see you're a man
who understands details, Mr Greene.
那些对我是最重要的
每个细节都很重要
They're most important to me.
Most important. All the little details.
噢不好意思
不知道你们在忙
Oh, dear. I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were busy.
-我们迟点来吧
-进来吧既然已经来了
- We can come back.
- Come in, now that you're here.
格林太太这位是我叔叔
奥克里先生
Mrs Greene,
I'd like you to meet my uncle, Mr Oakley.
查理叔叔这两位是
格林太太和波特太太
Uncle Charlie,
this is Mrs Greene and Mrs Potter.
格林太太波特小姐
Mrs Greene, Miss Potter.
是波特太太
Mrs Potter.
-我可不那麽认为
-是吗?
- Something about you made me think -
- Yes?
-怎麽了玛格莉?
-我们想购物但现在只有五块钱
- What did you want, Margaret?
- I need some money to go shopping.
做寡妇也有一点是好的
There's one good thing
in being a widow, isn't there?
就是不用问丈夫要钱花
You don't have to ask
your husband for money.
-给你
-噢谢谢
- Here you are.
- Oh, thank you.
再见奥克里先生
波特太太
- Goodbye, Mr Oakley.
- Mrs Potter.
再见格林太太
Bye, Mrs Greene.
好了格林先生
There. There you are, Mr Greene.
-查莉我们去吃午饭吧
-再见奥克里先生
- Charlie, let's see the town.
- Goodbye, Mr Oakley.
-再见格林先生
-有问题随时可以来查询
- Bye, Mr Greene.
- Call on us for advice anytime.
-谢谢
-祖送奥克里先生出门吧
- Thank you.
- Joe, you may see Mr Oakley out.
祖只要你醒目点
他的位置迟早\'是你的
Joe, keep your eyes open.
You'll have his job in a couple of years.
他回来了
Here he is.
那些做调查的人来了
早\'了一个小时啊
Those must be the questionnaire men.
They're a whole hour early.
-我不会见他们的
-别担心
I won't see them.
你不想的话就不见吧
我明白的
You don't have to if you don't want to.
I'll see that you don't.
小心他们对你母亲做什麽
The way they got around your mother.
我想她要警惕一点
I thought she'd have better sense.
-你好
- How do you do?
-你们应该就是来做调查的吧
-我是格翰牛顿太太
- You must have come to interview us.
- My name is Graham, Miss Newton.
-你好
-这位是桑德斯
- Oh, how do you do?
- And this is Fred Saunders.
你好   请进来
How do you do? Won't you come in?
-我去叫妈妈
-谢谢
- I'll call my mother.
- Thank you.
妈妈他们进来了
Mother, the government men are here.
请做
Will you sit down?
你们说是四点的
现在还没准备好啊
But you said 4:00. Nothing's ready now.
我丈夫还在银行
而这里...
My husband is still at the bank
and-and the house is -
我们就是想这样
牛顿太太
That's all we want now, Mrs Newton,
some pictures of the house.
桑德斯会在周围拍照
而我就问你问题
Saunders can get busy
and I'd like to ask a few questions.
好的但我希望你们
等我把房子收拾好了
Alright, but I do wish you'd waited
until I had the house looking its best.
我想在这里安放鲜花
还有在厨房里挂新的窗窗布
I wanted flowers around
and fresh curtains in the kitchen.
还有很多东西我想你们拍照的
And there are a lot of things
I don't want you to photograph.
-你们拥有这房子吗?
-不是房子拥有我们
- You said you own the house?
- Own it? It owns us.
有一样东西开始要修理的话
整间房子都要修理了
No sooner do I get one thing fixed
than something else gets broken.
要再刷一下油漆...
And then it needs fresh paint and th-
桑德斯先生
不好意思...
Mr Saunders, I'm very sorry
请不要给这张椅子拍照
but you simply cannot
take a picture with that chair in it.
-要套一个沙发套
-你们家有六个人?
- It needs a new slipcover.
- And there are, uh, six in your family?
-是五个
-五个?但是...
- Five.
- Five? But -
我叔叔只是来探望我们的
Well, my uncle ' s just visiting.
我说过他的
他是从东部来的
I told you about him.
He's here from the East.
我叔叔不希望有什麽麻烦
My uncle doesn't want to be bothered
with a lot of questions.
做调查的时候我们要...
Well, you see, on a survey, we usually -
他对调查不感兴趣...
He's not interested
in a survey
我答应过他不会骚扰他的
and I promised him
he wouldn ' t be bothered.
我们希望你们都参与
Well, we'd like it
if we could get all of you.
想了解你们做什麽
和想做些什麽
You know, your opinions,
what you do or what you want to do.
我叔叔的意见很特别的
我想你们不会接受
My uncle's opinions aren't average
and I'm afraid they wouldn't help you.
我想每个人都有自己的思想
I think when someone asks for privacy,
they should have it.
其实我们这次的目的是...
Well, we'll...
The whole idea of this thing is that -
格翰先生我想你们应该
选择另外的家庭
Mr Graham, perhaps
you'd better choose another family.
我们也有这样做的
但你们的家庭是...
We'll do anything you say, of course,
but this family seemed right and -
是一个很好的家庭
It is a nice family.
查莉你为什麽
不让他问下去呢?
Charlie, let the young men go ahead,
so long as they're here.
那好吧
Well, alright.
好的桑德斯
去拍些照片吧
OK. Saunders, go ahead
and get another shot.
牛顿太太可以告诉
我你丈夫在哪里工作吗?
Mrs Newton, what organisations
do you and your husband belong to?
在厨房照一张好吗?
How about a picture in the kitchen?
我想不是很适合
Well, I'm afraid the kitchen
isn't quite the way I'd like it.
过来
Come along.
牛顿太太
你要先打鸡蛋吧
If you'll start by breakin' an egg,
Mrs Newton.
噢不不应该先打蛋的
Oh, but you don't start a cake
by breaking an egg.
要先把牛油和糖放进去
You have to put
the butter and sugar in first.
有没有调查
我都不会先打蛋的
Survey or no survey,
I'm not going to start by breaking an egg.
我要做一个枫叶蛋糕
我弟弟很爱吃的
I thought I'd make a maple cake.
My brother Charles loves maple cake.
-你弟弟做什麽的?
-我想他什麽都做
What does your brother do?
I guess he just does about everything.
-是什麽工作?
-应该是做生意的男人都是那样
What does he do? He's just in business.
You know, the way men are.
我丈夫在银行
但我想查理是生意人
My husband works in a bank,
but I think Charles is just in business.
如果你要在
我打蛋的时候拍照
If you really want a picture
of me breaking an egg,
那就要等我把
牛油和糖放进去
you'll have to wait
till I cream the butter and sugar.
我会等的
I'll wait.
我可以到楼上看看吗?
I wonder if we could
take a look upstairs.
请你带我去吧
你妈妈会叫我的好的
You show us, and your mother can call us
when she's ready.
桑德斯先生
- Alright.
- If you'd rather wait, Mr Saunders.
加蛋的时间要很及时
Folding in the eggs
has to be done just right.
不能让它等得太久
I can ' t beat them and let them stand.
我一听到你打蛋的声音
就马上下来
The minute I hear you've
broken the eggs, I'll come right down.
好的
Yes.
我不知道你想找什麽
I really don't see
what you want to look up here for.
那间房是谁的?本来
是我的现在查理叔叔住著
Whose room is that? It's mine.
My uncle's using it now, though.
我想知道
里面的布局是怎样的
I'd like to see what your room looks like.
Typical girl, typical room.
但我叔叔正在休息
Typical of you to ask.
My uncle's resting.
我不想打扰他
I really don't want to disturb him.
-那是後楼梯吗?
-没错可以到大厅的
- Is there a back stairs?
- Mm-hm. Right down the hall.
我和你打赌
你叔叔不在里面
I'll bet you 50 cents
that your uncle isn't in there.
打赌很无聊的
Oh, betting's silly.
你只是想进去拍照
All you want to do
is photograph my room, doesn't he?
我知道叔叔在里面
- That's it.
- Besides, I know my uncle's in there.
但我还是认为他在里面
我们进去看看吧
Alright, I'll still bet he isn't.
Let me knock and see.
我先敲门
Oh, I'll knock.
查理叔叔?
Uncle Charlie?
查理叔叔
我们可以进来吗?
Uncle Charlie, may we come in?
-看到了吗?
-你说得对
- See?
- You were right.
不错的房间啊
可以拍几张照片吗?
Nice room. Do you mind if I take a picture
since he isn't here?
-我真的不想打扰你叔叔
-我知道
- I don't want to disturb your uncle.
- Oh, I suppose so.
但我想不到
谁会对我的房间感兴趣
But I really can't imagine
anyone being interested in my room.
我喜欢现在的颜色
我喜欢全部是白色
It's not the way I'd like it.
I'd like to have it yellow and white.
他想享受宁静啊
Might as well let him work in peace.
我想和他说几句
Besides, I'd like to talk to you.
你说我们是普通家庭
但我觉得很有意思
Your picking us as an average family
gave me a funny feeling.
-什麽有意思?
-我不知道
- What kind of a funny feeling?
- Oh, I don't know.
我想是我不想
做一个普通女孩吧
I guess I don't like to be and average girl
in an average family.
普通家庭才是好的
看看我
Average families are the best.
Look at me.
-我也是来自普通家庭的
-和我们一样普通?
- I'm from an average family.
- As average as ours?
当然是了
但我还不确定你们很普通
Sure.
Besides, I don't think you're average.
那是因为你们现在来这里
而不是前几天
Oh, that's because you see me now
instead of a few days ago.
我那时很灰暗
查理叔叔来了就改变了
I was in the dumps. Then Uncle Charlie
came and everything changed.
但你妈妈说他昨晚才到的
可能你...
But your mother said he came last night.
Maybe you just think -
我知道的
I don't think. I know.
很有趣每次我想东西的时候
总会想到查理叔叔
Funny, but when I think about how I feel,
I always come back to Uncle Charlie.
而你不想让我
觉得他很不简单吗?
Are you trying to tell me
I shouldn't think he's so wonderful?
-噢我只是...
-桑德斯先生?
- Oh, no. I -
- Mr Saunders?
我准备好打蛋了希望
桑德斯先生不会搞得很乱
- I'm ready with the eggs.
- Mr Saunders mustn't move anything.
-我叔叔是很整洁和挑剔的
-桑德斯先生也是的
- My uncle's awfully neat and fussy.
- Saunders is neat and fussy, too.
-这是你提起的叔叔吗?
-是的
- Is this your uncle?
- Yes, it is.
现在来一张走廊的
Now, for one of the hall.
桑德斯先生在
我房间拍了几张照片
Mr Saunders has been
taking pictures of my room.
我姐姐提醒你们
那些鸡蛋和蛋糕
My sister told me to remind you
about eggs and a cake.
我不想被拍照
我要拿回那底片
I don't like to be photographed.
I'll have to ask you for the film.
-噢查理叔叔
-请给我
- Oh, Uncle Charlie.
- Give it to me, please.
给他吧桑德斯
Give it to him, Fred.
真可惜牛顿太太
的照片也在里面
That's too bad. There's a picture
of Mrs Newton on this film.
不好意思桑德斯先生
我准备好加蛋了
- Excuse me.
- The eggs are ready.
我不能再让它等著了
I can't let them stand another minute.
-那是最後一卷胶卷了
-噢
That was my last roll of film.
桑德斯先生
给查理叔叔拍照...
Mr Saunders took
Uncle Charlie's picture by mistake
查理叔叔把胶卷拿了
and Uncle Charlie made him
give him back the roll.
他不是在开玩笑的
He wasn't joking
about not wanting to be photographed.
我们都不想
有什麽家庭纠纷
We didn't want to start a family feud.
我们明天再来
看你做蛋糕吧
I'll get you
making the cake again tomorrow.
我明天不会做蛋糕了
I won't be
making a cake again tomorrow.
我要做一些
很重要的事情
I want to help an important work,
but I cannot go on making cakes.
你已经帮我们了
牛顿太太
You have helped, Mrs Newton.
我还想问一下
And now I'd like to ask another favour.
今天晚上可以约你的女儿
出去吗?我想四处看看
Could I borrow your daughter?
I'd like to look around the town.
-安妮?
-是查莉
- Ann?
- Charlie.
安妮会好些
她什麽都知道
Ann would be better.
Ann knows everything about everybody.
-查莉
-如果查莉不介意的话
- Charlie.
- Well, if, uh, Charlie doesn't mind.
-我不介意
-太好了
- I don't mind.
- Swell.
-再见牛顿太太
-再见
- Goodbye, then, Mrs Newton.
- Goodbye.
-六点半好吗?
-六点半
- 6:30?
- 6:30.
-好的再见
-再见
- OK. Goodbye.
- Bye.
-再见桑德斯先生
再见
- Bye, Mr Saunders.
- Bye.
再见
Goodbye.
看来他是一个
不错的年轻人啊
He seems like a nice young man.
你不是要和
卡芙琳去看电影吗?
But I thought you were
going to the movies with Catherine.
我会告诉她我有点不舒服
Oh, I'll tell her
I don't feel well or something.
-你好啊查莉
-你们好啊卡芙琳雪莉
- Hello, Charlie.
- Well... hello, Catherine. Hello, Shirley.
-你们好
-这位是格翰他刚来这里
- Hello.
- This is Jack Graham. He's in town.
-你好
- How do you do?
- Hello.
-你的喉咙好点了吗查莉?
-好很多了谢谢
- How's your throat, Charlie?
- Oh, much better. Thank you.
比尔在问你的事呢
Bill Forest was asking about you.
噢比尔?
Oh. Bill Forest?
再见了
Well, uh... goodbye.
-再见
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
我知道你其实是什麽人
I know what you are, really.
你是侦探
You're a detective. There's something
the matter and you're a detective.
-有些事情是侦探会做的
-听我说查莉
- Charlie, listen.
- I don't want to listen.
我不想听你们根本
就不是来做调查
Why, you're not on a survey at all.
你对我们说谎
你们骗了我妈妈
You lied to us. You lied to Mother.
你们只是想进我们家里
You just wanted to get in our house.
Police.
就是那样
That's what it is.
你们为什麽要骗我们?
What do you want with us?
Why are you here, lying to us?
查莉你要听我说
你一定要相信我
Look, Charlie, you've got to listen to me.
You've got to trust me.
你说谎也要相信你吗?
When you've done nothing but lie?
我知道你并不是
想和我约会
And you probably didn't want to
take me out at all the way I thought.
你只是想问我很多问题
You just wanted to ask me
a lot of questions.
我有那样做吗有吗?
Have I asked you a lot of questions?
Have I?
好了我的确是侦探
还做得很糟糕
Alright, I'm a detective.
A pretty bad one.
你听我说几句好吗?
Now, won't you even listen to me?
-为什麽你要骗我?
-我必须那样做
- Why should I when you lied to me?
- I had to.
我来这里的目的
是为了一个男人不是你
When I came here to find a man,
I hadn't counted on you.
-不是你妈妈和你家人
-一个男人?什麽男人?
- I hadn't counted on your family.
- Find a man? What man?
我们在追踪一个在逃的人
There's a man loose in this country.
We're after him.
我们知道的很少
连他的样子都不知道
We don't know much.
We don't even know what he looks like.
查莉你对你叔叔了解有多少?
Charlie, think. How much
do you know about your uncle?
他是我妈妈的弟弟
他有什麽问题?
Why, he's my mother's brother.
What's he got to do with it?
我们要找的人
可能是你叔叔
This man we want may be your uncle.
噢我不相信
别再烦著我
Oh, I don't believe you.
Go away and leave me alone.
我们追踪的那个男人
很可能就是你叔叔
We're after one man.
Your uncle may be that man.
但在东部还有
另一个男人在被追捕
But in the East, there's another man
who's being hunted too,
从麻省到缅因
他可能就是那个人
through Massachusetts and into Maine.
He may be the one.
我叔叔没做什麽
My uncle hasn't done anything.
他知道那会对我妈妈不好
He knows it would kill
my mother if he did.
他是我妈妈的弟弟
就像罗杰和我一样
He's her younger brother,
just like Roger is mine.
他们为什麽不把
在东部那人捉了?
Why don't they arrest
that man in the East?
你们为什麽还要烦我们?
Why don't you go away
and leave us alone?
查莉我们晚餐时
谈起各自的亲人...
Charlie, when we were eating tonight
and talking about our folks
就像平常人一样
and what we'd done and how we felt,
we were like two ordinary people.
我们都在同样环境中成长
We'd been brought up about the same.
-我们彼此都有好感
-噢现在已不重要了
- You liked me and I liked you.
- Oh, it doesn't matter now.
什麽不重要这点才重要
What do you mean, "It doesn't matter"?
It's the only thing that does.
如果不是你的叔叔...
If it weren't for you,
you don't think I ' d care
我早\'就把他逮捕了
知道吗?
how or where I caught up
with your uncle, do you?
因为如果他真的是我们要的人
我们就要捉住他
Because if he's the guy, I'm going to
catch up with him. Remember that.
你必须保守秘密
And you're going to keep
your mouth shut.
因为你是个很好的女孩
如果你知道了...
You're going to keep your mouth shut
because you're such a nice girl
你就会帮你叔叔
you'd help if you knew
your uncle was the man we wanted.
-我不会帮你们的
-我知道你会的
- I wouldn't help you.
- And I know you would.
让我再给你一个好些的条件
And I'm trying to make it easier for you.
如果你叔叔真的是那个人
我们会平静地把他从这里带走
If your uncle's the man we want,
we'll get him out of town quietly.
-我们不会在这里逮捕他
-在这?在妈妈面前逮捕他?
- We won't arrest him here.
- Arrest him here? With mother -
我想对你说我们不会的
I'm trying to tell you we won ' t.
-求你了查莉
-我什麽也不会说的
- Please, Charlie.
- I won't say anything.
噢送我回家吧!
Oh, take me home!
晚安查莉
Good night, Charlie.
你们发现做错了
就一定很有趣
It's going to be funny
when you find out you're wrong.
晚安
Good night.
-你好啊查莉回来了吗?
-是的爸爸
- Hello, Charlie. Home already?
- Oh, yes, Dad.
外面空气很好
我想出去呼吸一下
It's so nice out, I thought
I'd get some air before I went to bed.
你最好快点回来
查理叔叔找你
You better run in. Your Uncle Charlie's
been asking about you.
我会在後门上去的
I think I'll just go up the back way.
我很累不是很想说话
I- I'm tired and I don't feel like talking.
好的换衣服吧
Alright. Suit yourself.
小心照顾自己啊
- Take care of yourself.
- Mm-hm.
-晚安贺博
-晚安查莉
- Good night, Herb.
- Good night, Charlie.
晚安查莉
Good night, Charlie.
我们在说什麽贺博?
What were we saying, Herb?
Did I notice what?
觉得有点什麽不妥吗...
Well, did you taste anything funny
你今晚在我家喝的咖啡?
about that coffee you had
at my house this evening?
没有啊
No. It tasted all right.
这就对了
那里面有点不同
That's what I mean. It wasn't all right.
-放了什麽?
-一点苏打水
- Put something in it?
- Put a little soda.
如果我放毒药的话
也是这份量
About the same amount that I'd have used
if I'd wanted to use poison.
你不说我还不察觉呢
Well, you don't say?
I never tasted a thing.
当然我连苏打
也察觉不到
Of course, I might not notice the soda.
更别提无色无味的毒药
You'd notice the soda more
than you would the poison.
如果是的话
你现在早\'死了
For all you knew, you might
just as well be dead now.
-安妮还没睡吗?
-是啊
- Aren't you asleep yet, Ann?
- Uh-uh.
查莉你在干嘛?
Charlotte, what are you doing?
噢我在找我看过的新闻
Oh, I'm just looking for a recipe
I thought I saw,
但这已经给撕破了--
but it's just so torn up.
图书馆里什麽报纸都有
They have papers in the "libarry",
new ones and old ones.
柯克然小姐会帮你找的
Miss Corcoran will get them out for you.
就算你剪下来一点
她都不会发现的
She won't even notice
if you cut out a little, bitty recipe.
那也不是什麽重要的东西
Oh, it's not that important.
图书馆几时关门?
What time does the library close?
如果你平时多去的话
就会知道是9点
If you read as much as you should,
you'd know it closes at 9:00.
这样啊那我明天才去吧
Oh, well.
If I think about it, maybe I'll go tomorrow.
你该睡了
You really ought to go to sleep, Ann.
回去!回去!回去!
Get back there!
Get back! Get back!
查莉等一下
知道我为什麽在这吗?
Just a moment, Charlie.
What do you think I am out here for?
对不起诺顿警官
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr Norton.
没事了走吧
Alright. Go ahead.
噢柯克然小姐
请让我进去!
Oh! Miss Corcoran, please let me in.
求求你!
Oh, please!
太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you.
查莉你真是的
明知道这里9点关门
Really, Charlie. You know as well as I do
the library closes at 9:00.
如果我这次给你例外
以後还得了
If I make one exception,
I'll have to make a thousand.
对不起柯克然小姐
我要找出那报纸
I'm sorry, Mrs Corcoran, but there is something
in the paper I've got to see.
太令我惊讶了
你都不为别人著想
I'm surprised at you, Charlie.
No consideration.
-我只需要一分钟
-你一大早\'又不来
- Oh, I'll only be a minute.
- You've got all day to come here.
真不知道你为啥
夜晚赶来这里
I don't know why you want
to rush in here tonight like a madwoman.
我只给你三分钟
I'll give you just three minutes.
老天保佑不要是坏消息
Can't be anything really awful.
我会证明他不是的
I'll prove to him it isn't.
第三版--
Page three -
你好
Hello.
-查莉在哪?
-她还在睡我不想吵醒她
- Where's Charlie?
- Still asleep. I don't want to wake her.
-查莉还在睡吗?
-不她刚醒来
- Charlie still asleep?
- No, she just woke up.
我不该让她睡那麽久
但她好像很累
I shouldn't have let her sleep so long,
but she needed it.
她有点不舒服
她会下来吃饭的
She doesn't look quite herself.
She'll be down for dinner.
妈妈让我来捣碎这些
Mother, let me finish mashing those.
我来弄晚餐吧
I'll fix the rest of dinner
and get it on the table.
你去跟查理叔叔聊吧
You go talk to Uncle Charlie.
-你觉得怎麽样?
-我没事
- How do you feel?
- Fine.
我累极了
睡得死死的
I must have been tired. I slept like a log.
查理叔叔找你很多次了
他很喜欢你
Uncle Charlie was asking for you again.
He's fond of you.
那年轻人也来过两次
我说你睡了
That nice young man came to ask
after you. I told him you were asleep.
我又恢复精神了
这肉汁弄好了吗?
I'm rested now. Is the gravy made?
你又在哼那华尔兹曲了
Now you're humming that waltz.
Please don't hum that tune anymore.
我好不容易才忘了它
I've just got it out of my head
and don't want it started again.
不要再哼了
Please remember, don't hum that tune.
不要每次都站起来
And don't keep getting up
every few minutes.
只要像个淑女那样
静静坐著
You just sit there and be a real lady.
那好吧
至少我能把汤端出去
Alright, if you say so,
but at least I can carry in the soup.
罗杰快洗手!
祖查理吃饭了
Roger, wash your hands!
Joe. Charles. Dinner.
妈妈安妮我说过
不要把东西挂在耳後
- Mama -
- Ann, don't put things behind your ear.
别低声说谁都知道
你在说坏话
And don't whisper.
Anyone could hear you a block away.
我能跟你坐吗?
May I sit by you at the table?
跟我?我还以为
你想跟查理叔叔坐呢
By me? I should think
you'd want to sit by Uncle Charlie.
-不我想跟你坐
-为什麽想换?
- No, I want to sit by you.
- Why do you want to change?
妈妈就让她换吧
Mother, let her change if she wants to.
罗杰说不介意
Roger doesn't mind.
他当然不介意
但查理叔叔会不能
No, certainly not.
Uncle Charlie might think... Certainly not.
-妈妈让她换吧
-好吧安妮总是有怪念头
- Mother, let her change.
- OK, but Ann has some foolish ideas.
你们都去饭厅吧
Go in the dining room, both of you.
什麽事了?
安妮不跟我坐了吗?
What's going on here?
Have I lost my little girl?
罗杰想跟你坐
Roger wanted to sit next to you,
我想让孩子们换换座位
and I thought it would be nice
if the children took turns.
-我才不想--
-不想什麽罗杰?
- I never...
- Never what, Roger?
没事安妮快来帮我
- Nothing.
- Come, Ann. Come and help me.
祖!   我不该把报纸
带到饭桌上没特别的新闻
Joe! I brought it in by mistake.
Nothing special in it.
-查理想看一下吗?
-谢谢祖
- Want to look at the headlines, Charles?
- Thank you, Joe.
罗杰喝汤不要发出声音
Roger, don't make so much noise
with your soup.
如果他能像马一样
把嘴唇贴近点就好了
If he holds his lips together, he
could draw it carefully, like a horse.
-别那麽恶心
-我能把面包沾进去吗?
- Don't be disgusting.
- May I dip my bread in it?
-查莉呢?
-她在准备晚餐
- Where's Charlie?
- She wanted to serve dinner.
-她很快就来
-说得对祖
- She ' II be in in a minute.
- You're right, Joe.
没什麽特别新闻
她来了!
Nothing special tonight. Oh, here she is!
-我可爱的外甥女来了
-我想知道你睡了多久
- Here ' s my girl.
- How many hours did you sleep?
只要你告诉我什麽时候睡
If you could tell me
the exact minute you went to sleep,
你什麽时候醒
如果你中途有醒来...
the exact minute you woke up,
if you woke up in between
那你醒了多久
and how long you stayed awake
each time you woke up,
然後我就能准确告诉你
then I could tell you exactly -
你今晚准睡不著
没人能睡一整天的
You won't sleep tonight.
Nobody who sleeps all day can.
我昨晚做梦
I slept all right, and I kept dreaming,
关于你的噩梦
查理叔叔
perfect nightmares
about you, Uncle Charlie.
关于我的噩梦?
Nightmares about me?
你在火车上
想躲避某些东西...
You were on a train,
running away from something
我很高兴看到你在火车上
and when I saw you on the train,
I felt terribly happy.
看到查理叔叔在
火车上又怎会高兴呢?
How could you feel happy
seeing Uncle Charlie on a train?
我才不要他离开呢
我要他留在这
I don't want to see him on a train.
I hope he stays here forever.
他始终要走
我们要面对现实
Well, he has to leave sometime.
We have to face the facts.
我欣赏面对现实的人
I like people who face facts.
我们也不一定
要遇到那些事
Well, we're not going
to face any such facts as those.
安妮你要看笑话吗?
Oh, Ann,
would you like to see the funnies?
我长大了
一个星期还看两本书
I'm too old for funnies. I read two books
a week. I took a sacred oath I would.
而且在饭桌上
阅读是不礼貌的
Besides, no one's allowed to read
at the table. It isn't polite.
不要顶撞长辈!
Don't correct your elders!
不关她事艾玛
是我忘了
She's right, Emmy.
I'm forgetting my manners.
祖我不是说你带报纸来
Joe, I'm going to blame this paper on you.
罗杰去冰箱
找那红瓶子的酒来
Roger, go to the icebox and bring me
a big, red bottle you'll find there.
现在能把报纸扔走
爸爸读过你也读过
You can throw the paper away.
Dad's read it, you've read it.
今晚我们
也不玩什麽游戏了
We don't need to play any
games with it tonight.
安妮帮查莉
把水果拿出来
Ann, you can help
Charlie carry the vegetables.
我准备晚餐
时就看到那瓶酒
I saw that bottle
when I was getting dinner.
圣.波罗说过「
为了胃部著想而喝点酒」
St Paul said, "Take a little wine
for thy stomach's sake. "
餐酒...
听起来多暧昧!
Wine for dinner sounds so gay!
记得老琼斯的大女儿
结婚时的酒吗?
Remember they had the champagne
when the oldest Jones girl got married?
那是正宗
法国勃艮第红酒啊
This is sparkling burgundy.
只要一口
我就知道是勃艮第红酒
One sip and I'll be calling it
"sparkling burgledy. "
我还是不要喝了
Maybe I'd better not take any.
噢...进口的
Oh... imported.
法国进口和那些斜纹?
Imported Frankie and his tweeds?
他把斜纹刻在拐杖上
And his loaded cane.
他把什麽都刻上去!
His loaded everything!
罗杰拿四苹杯子出来
Roger, go get four
of the small glasses with stems.
我答应俱乐部的格林太太
你给女士们演讲
Charles, I promised Mrs Greene of our
club that you'd talk to the ladies.
我讲什麽好呢?
一般都是时事和见闻
What am I going to talk about?
Travel or current events?
不要讲时事
我们听得多了
Oh, not current events.
We get current events.
什麽类型的观众?
Who'll my audience be?
像我一样的家庭主妇
Oh, women like myself.
Busy with our homes, most of us.
这城镇的女士们都很忙
Women keep busy in towns like this.
在大城市就不同
中年的寡妇
In the cities it's different.
Middle-aged widows, husbands dead,
她们死去的丈夫
穷尽一生积累财富
husbands who ' ve spent their lives
making fortunes, working and working,
留下一大笔钱给
愚蠢的妻子
and then they die and leave their money
to their wives, their silly wives.
这些没用的妻子们怎麽做?
And what do the wives do,
these useless women?
她们出入
最豪华奢侈的酒店
You see them in the best hotels
every day by the thousands,
吃喝玩乐
挥霍度日
drinking the money, eating the money,
花钱如流水
losing the money at bridge,
playing all day and all night,
浑身都是铜臭味
smelling of money.
唯一值得引以为荣的
是她们的珠宝
Proud of their jewellery,
but of nothing else.
讨厌衰老肥胖
贪心的女人
Horrible, faded, fat, greedy women.
但她们是人啊!
活生生的人啊!
But they're alive! They're human beings.
是吗?是吗查莉?
Are they? Are they, Charlie?
她们不像贪得
无厌的动物吗?怎麽样?
Are they human,
or are they fat, wheezing animals? Hm?
动物变老
肥得不能动了又怎麽样?
And what happens to animals when
they get too fat and too old?
我好像在这就演讲了
Well, I seem to be making
my speech right here.
不要在俱乐部说这些!
你会被赶下台的
Don't talk about women like that
in front of my club! You'll be lynched.
波特太太也去
她跟我提起你
That nice Mrs Potter's going to be there.
She was asking me about you.
格林把她带去俱乐部
演讲後我帮你介绍
The Greenes are bringing her here to
the party I'm having for you afterwards.
祖贺博来了
Joe, it's Herbert.
他总是在我们吃饭时来
He always comes when we're eating.
晚安牛顿太太
Good evening, Mrs Newton.
-晚安奥克里先生
-晚安
- Good evening, Mr Oakley.
- Good evening.
贺博你妈妈还好吗?
Well, Herb, how's your mother?
噢一般吧
Oh, she's just middling.
-吃饭了吗?
-一小时前吃过了
- Had your dinner?
- Oh, I had mine an hour ago.
你们果然新潮
这麽晚才吃饭啊
You folks are getting pretty stylish.
Having dinner later every evening.
哈哈!
Ha ha!
-祖
-怎麽啦?
- Joe.
- Huh?
-祖我摘了些蘑菇
-你没告诉我
- Joe, I-I picked some mushrooms.
- You don't say?
蘑菇令你想起什麽吗?
Mushrooms mean anything to you, Joe?
我在外面吃的肉排
还不如这个美味呢
I eat 'em on my steak when I'm out
and the meat's not good enough as it is.
我送你些蘑菇
你会吃吗?
If I brought you some mushrooms,
would you eat 'em?
可能会吧
为什麽这样说?
Suppose I would. Why?
对了我最多只会
被判一般杀人罪
Then I've got it. The worst I'd be
accused of would be manslaughter.
造成意外死亡
乾净利落
Doubt if I'd get that.
Accidental death, pure and simple.
一篮子的蘑菇里...
只有两三个有毒
A basket of good mushrooms and...
two or three poisonous ones.
不无知的陪审团
只会注意有毒的
No, no. Innocent party might
get the poisonous ones.
我在刮胡子时想到一方法
I thought of something better
when I was shaving.
浴盆把你倒挂著
而你的腿放在外面
这有人做过了但兵不厌诈
A bath tub. Pull the legs out
from under you, hold you down.
你们怎麽了?
Oh, what's the matter with you two?
非得整天都说著杀人吗?
Do you always have to
talk about killing people?
我们不是说杀其他人
We're not talking about killing people.
贺博想杀我
而我想杀他
Herb's talking about killing me,
and I'm talking about killing him.
这是你爸爸的娱乐方式
It's your father's way of relaxing.
他就不能用其他方式吗?
Can't he find some other way to relax?
除了研究毒药
就不能有点安宁吗?
Can't we have a little peace and quiet
without dragging in poisons all the time?
查莉!她在胡说八道
Charlie!
She doesn ' t make sense talking like that.
真令人担心罗杰
找她回来
I'm worried about her.
Roger, bring her back.
我跟著她
你们继续吃
I'll go. You stay and finish dinner.
I'll catch up with her.
她怎麽了?
What's wrong with her?
-对不起诺顿警官
-你总是在街上乱跑
- Excuse me, Mr Norton.
- You're always running around at night.
-你昨晚匆匆忙忙去哪?
-只是有点事做
- Where were you hurrying to last night?
- Just doing an errand.
-这位是你的叔叔吗?
-是的
- Is this your uncle I've heard about?
- Yes.
-诺顿警官这是查理叔叔
-很高兴认识你你叫?
- Uncle Charlie, Mr Norton.
- Glad to know you. What's the name?
查理.奥克里
很高兴认识你
Oakley. Charles Oakley. Nice to meet you.
管好你的外甥女
下次我可要给她开罚单
Better keep your eye on your niece.
I'll have to give her a ticket for speeding.
在马路上横冲直撞
是违法的知道吗?
- City ordinance about running.
- Hear that, Charlie?
不要知法犯法
我会看好她的了
Don't want to break the law.
I'll take care of her.
晚安
- Good night.
查莉怎麽了?
发生什麽事了?
What's the matter, Charlie?
What's wrong?
-我要跟你谈谈
-你又弄痛我了
- I want to talk to you.
- You're hurting my arm again.
-跟我来
-不我没来过这些地方
- Come in here with me.
- I can't. I don't go to places like this.
来
Go on in.
-带我来这干嘛?
-在哪里又有什麽关系呢?
- Why'd you bring me here?
- What does it matter where we are?
-你好查莉
-你好
Hello, Charlie. Hello.
路易斯你好查理叔叔
这是路易斯.菲治你好
Hello, Louise.
Uncle Charlie, Louise Finch.
-这是我的叔叔
-我是查莉的同学
- This is my uncle.
- I was in Charlie's class in school.
没想过你会来这里
I sure was surprised to see you come in.
I never thought I'd see you here.
我来这里有两周了
I been here two weeks.
Lost my job over at Kern's.
我在全镇一半的酒吧干过
要点什麽?
I've been in half the restaurants in town.
What'll you have, Charlie?
不了给她一杯
姜汁我要白兰地
- Nothing, thank you.
- A ginger ale for her, a brandy for me.
-查莉怎麽了
-怎麽了?
- Well, Charlie?
- Well?
你知道很多吗?
那家伙告诉你些东西
Think you know something, don't you?
That young fellow told you something.
杰克?凭什麽说
他知道你的事?
Jack?
Why should he know anything about you?
-查莉我不想
我们之间有什麽误会
Charlie, something's come between us.
I don't want that to happen.
因为我们是老朋友啊
而且...
Why, we're old friends.
我们就像双胞胎
More than that. We're like twins.
-是你自己说
-查理叔叔别碰我
- You said so yourself.
- Don't touch me, Uncle Charlie.
他跟你说了什麽?
What did that boy tell you?
他没说什麽
我也想他不知道你的事
He's got nothing to do with it. I hope
he never knows anything about you.
查莉
你真是细心可爱的女孩
Charlie,
you're a pretty understanding sort of girl.
如果你听到
关于我的传闻
If you've heard
some little things about me,
我想你肯定
不会把它当真
I guess you're a woman of the world
enough to overlook them.
人人都看出
你是家里的支柱
You're the head of your family, Charlie.
Anyone can see that.
我老了我十六岁
就开始到处漂泊
I'm not so old. I've been chasing
around the globe since I was sixteen.
我做了些蠢事
I guess I've done
some pretty foolish things,
犯了愚蠢的错误
made some pretty foolish mistakes.
没什麽大不了
只是...可笑的错误
Nothing serious, just... foolish.
查莉别妄自猜测
Oh, Charlie, now,
don't start imagining things.
你怎麽能做出这种事?
你是我的叔叔
How could you do such things?
You're my uncle,
我妈的弟弟
my mother's brother.
我们都认为
你是很成功的人
We thought you were
the most wonderful man in the world.
-世界上最成功的人
-查莉你知道什麽?
- The most wonderful and the best.
- Charlie, what do you know?
让你们久等了
我们真的很忙
I'm sorry I was so long.
We're awful busy.
这是谁的?
不是很漂亮吗?
Whose is it? Ain't it beautiful?
我一直都想
拥有这样的戒指
I'd just die for a ring like that.
这戒指简直让我目眩
Yes sir, for a ring like that,
I'd just about die.
我最爱珠宝--真的珠宝
I love jewellery, real jewellery.
我根本不用就能辩出真假
Notice I didn't even have to ask
if it was real. You can tell.
-我知道
-我要多一杯白兰地
- I can.
- Bring me another brandy.
坐下
Sit down.
坐下!
Sit down!
你认为自己知道多少?
You think you know something,
don't you?
你以为你很聪明
You think you're the clever little girl
who knows something.
但你不知道的还多著呢
There's so much you don't know.
So much.
你知道什麽?
What do you know, really?
你只不过是个普通的女孩
You're just an ordinary little girl
living in an ordinary little town.
每天从床上醒来
无　无虑
You wake up every day and know there's
nothing in the world to trouble you.
平平淡淡地过日子...
You go through your ordinary little day.
晚上睡在安稳的床
做些无聊的梦
At night, you sleep your ordinary sleep
filled with peaceful, stupid dreams.
是我给你带来噩梦
And I brought you nightmares.
对吗?还是一个谎言?
Or did I?
Or was it a silly, inexpert, little lie?
你生活在梦境里
看不到现实
You live in a dream.
You're a sleepwalker, blind.
你知道外面的世界是怎样吗?
How do you know
what the world is like?
你能想像那就像
猪圈般肮脏吗?
Do you know the world is a foul sty?
你知道周围是带著
面具的卑贱小人吗?
Do you know if you ripped
the fronts off houses, you'd find swine?
这个该死的世界
有谁在乎发生什麽?
The world's a hell.
What does it matter what happens in it?
醒醒吧查莉
你的聪明去哪了?
Wake up, Charlie.
Use your wits. Learn something!
查莉你走了吗?
You goin', Charlie?
-查莉你会帮我吗?
-帮你?
- Charlie, will you help me?
- Help you?
我们身上淌著一样的血
一周前我几乎绝望
The same blood flows through our veins.
I was at the end of my rope.
我太累了我受够了
Oh, I'm so tired. There's an end
to the running a man can do.
你没法想像那种累
我准备--
You'll never know what it's like
to be so tired. I was going to...
嗯...我想离开这里
帮帮我查莉
Then I got the idea of coming out here.
It's my last chance, Charlie.
给我一次机会
Give it to me.
格翰和那个家伙不知道
Graham and the other fellow,
they don't know.
如果抓到东部的那个
嫌疑犯我就--
There's a man in the east they suspect,
and if they get him, I'll...
查莉给我一次机会
Charlie, give me this last chance.
好吧那你走!
Take your chance. Go!
我会走的查莉
给我几天时间
I'll go, Charlie. Just give me a few days.
为你妈妈著想
她知道後会疯的
Think of your mother.
It'll kill your mother.
我知道她会受不了的
Yes, it would kill my mother.
那你几天後要离开这里
Take your few days.
See that you get away from here.
你知道如果
我被抓了後果是什麽?
You realise what it'll mean
if they get me?
坐电椅
The electric chair.
查莉全靠你了
你要帮我啊
Charlie, you've got to help me.
你说我们不仅是叔叔
与外甥女关系
You said yourself we're no ordinary uncle
and niece, no matter what I've done.
你先进去我跟著来
You go in. I'll be in in a minute.
-家是最好的地方
-查莉呢?
- Home, sweet home.
- Where's Charlie?
-她在外面别担心
-她怎麽了?
- She's outside. Don't worry about her.
- What was the matter?
她有点烦躁
我让她去散散心
She was a little edgy. I persuaded her
to go for a walk. She's calmer now.
-那就好给你留了甜品
-冰淇淋苏打
- I'm so glad. I've saved dessert for you.
- We had an ice-cream soda.
噢!你快点上床吧!
Oops-a-daisy! Off to bed you go!
-罗杰过来!
-不!
- Roger, come here!
- No!
我来对付她
嘘!安妮!
There's my girl. Psst! Ann!
你好!
你一定是藏著什麽
Hello!
You must be trying to hide or something.
-我没有
-只有藏著东西的人才会说嘘
- We're not hiding.
- People who are hiding say "psst".
-我不想在星期天吵闹
-听著安妮
- We just don't want to yell on Sunday.
- Look, Ann.
叫你姐姐来一下
小声点我们在这等
Ask your sister to run over here.
Just ask her quietly. We'll wait here.
-我爸爸跟你爸爸有过节吗?
-我爸爸?
- Did my father have a feud with yours?
- My father?
不然你不会
瞒著别人叫她来
Because if they didn't, there's no sense
in my asking Charlotte quietly.
妈妈不介意的
她说女人就该生儿育女
Mama won't care. She thinks
girls ought to marry and settle down.
-我读过一本书--
-叫她来吧别卖弄文才了
- In a book I'm reading -
- Just ask her, Ann. Don't be literary.
-好吧
-记住由我来说
- Alright.
- Remember, I'm doing all the talking.
-你好
-你好你好凯瑟琳
- Hello.
早\'上好格翰警官
Good morning, Mr Graham.
凯瑟琳
这是桑德斯警官
Catherine, this is Mr Saunders.
-你好
- How do you do?
-安妮说你有事找我
-桑德斯有事跟你说
- Ann says you want to speak to me.
- Saunders wants to.
来安妮，跟凯瑟琳说说吧
Come on, Ann.
Tell Catherine the story of Dracula.
来吧，凯瑟琳
Come on, Catherine.
-你想怎样?
-让他们走远点再说
- What do you want?
- Let them get a little bit ahead.
我想说关于
你叔叔的照片的事
It's about that photograph we took,
the one of your uncle.
-你给回他了他也许烧掉
-不是那张
- He probably burned it.
- Not that one, he hasn't.
我们给了张错误的相片
We gave him the wrong film.
我们拿真正的照片
跟东部那边联系
We got the picture alright.
We wired it East.
那里的证人能认出
谁是我们通缉的罪犯
They've got witnesses can identify
the man we want from that picture.
-什麽能认出是他?
-对了
- What do you mean, identify him?
- Just what I said.
当证人看到照片
就能知道他是否罪犯
When the witnesses see that picture,
we'll know whether Oakley's the man.
-我们准备跟那边联系
-那查理叔叔会--
- We're waiting for the wire now.
- And then Uncle Charlie will be -
对了就是这样
That's right. That's the way it is.
格翰想你可以让他离开
这会好点--
Graham thought you could get your uncle
to leave town now. It would be better -
我会的一定会!
你能给多长时间?
I've got to, haven't I? I've got to!
What's the most time you'll give me?
两小时内
我会叫他离开的!
- Two hours.
- I'll make him leave!
你为什麽肯定
他是我们要找的人?
You seem pretty sure
he's the man we want. Why?
-没有原因我只是害怕
-你是唯一能肯定的人
No reason why. I'm just scared.
You're the ones who seem sure.
-我不能让这里有事
-你知道他干过什麽?
- I couldn't bear anything happening here.
- You know what he's done?
-不我不想听!
-希望你知道
- No, I don't want to hear!
- Well, I want you to get this.
我们想帮你
把知道的都告诉我们吧!
We're doing you a favour. If you know
anything more about your uncle, tell us.
我们还想知道
他什麽时候离开
We also want to know
when and how he leaves town.
-如果你瞒著我们--
-不我会告诉你的
- If you hold out on us -
- I won't. I'll tell you.
走多一步
你会弄伤妈妈的背
Step on a crack,
you'll break your mother's back.
我们都想相信你
I wish I knew we could trust you.
我保证不会再帮他了
I won't do anything to help him,
I promise.
但你不能让
我去暗中监视他
But you can't ask me to spy on him.
我们来个交易
我叫他离开
We've made a bargain.
I'll get him to leave. That's all I'll do.
查莉他是危险人物
一旦离开我们视线范围--
Think, Charlie. The man's dangerous.
If he gets away from us -
我不想知道他做什麽
我会遵守诺言
I don't want to hear what he'll do.
We've made a bargain. I'll keep it.
他走的时候
我会通知你
I'll let you know when he leaves.
万一他不是通缉犯
那有好看的
Funny if he turned out
to be the wrong man. Could be.
-安妮
-我把妈妈的背弄伤了三次
- Ann!
- I broke my mother's back three times.
你还没说罗斯小姐
是否嫁给了有钱人...
Not bad. You didn't finish telling me
whether Miss Rose married the rich guy,
-或者她的新欢
-你跟她那麽熟啊?
- or the one she was in love with.
- How long have you two such friends?
我们在玩游戏
我问她答
Oh, we play games. I ask questions.
She knows all the answers.
麻烦的是
我弄不懂她在胡扯什麽
The only trouble is
I can't make out what she's making up.
我不会胡扯，说的都是书本上的知识
I never make up anything.
I get everything from my books.
我说的都是事实
They're all true.
安妮来吧
我们去帮忙做饭吧再见
Come on, Ann. We'd better get home
and help with dinner. Goodbye.
再见再见
格翰警官桑德斯警官
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Mr Graham. Mr Saunders.
-再见凯瑟琳
-再见
- Goodbye, Catherine.
- Come on, Catherine.
为啥不去摘些花
点缀一下晚餐?越简单越好
- Why not pick flowers for the table?
- Simple flowers are the best.
-不用是紫罗兰的
-要是我在南方出生就好了
- I didn't ask for orchids.
- I wish I'd been born in the South.
南方的女人很有魅力
她们戴著手套摘花
Southern women have a lot of charm.
They pick flowers with gloves on.
-再见凯瑟琳
-再见查莉晚饭後见
- Goodbye, Catherine.
- Goodbye, Charlie. See you after dinner.
再见
Bye.
-安妮你好
-你好
- Hello, Ann.
- Hello.
教堂怎麽样?
够座位吗?有人要让座吗?
How was church, Charlie? Did you
count the house? Turn anybody away?
不够了
No, room enough for everyone.
很好
I'm glad to hear that.
演出一段时间了
观众会陆续减少
Show's been running such a long time,
I thought attendance might be falling off.
电台有什麽新闻吗?
Anything special on the noon broadcast?
说抓到了另一个
嫌疑犯--玛丽寡妇杀手
They caught that other fellow,
the Merry Widow Murderer.
-真的吗?哪里?
-缅因州的波特兰
- They did, did they? Where?
- State of Maine. Portland.
不算真正的抓到
他逃避警方的追捕
Didn't catch him exactly.
He was running away from the police,
跑进了飞机场
躲到飞机的推进器後
and they cornered him at the airport
and he ran into the propeller of a plane.
-噢!
-他被切得肢离破碎
- Oh, boy!
- Cut him all to pieces.
只能从衣服辩认
Had to identify him by his clothes.
他的衣服印著「C」「O」
省略号「H」
His shirts were all initialled,
"C," "O," apostrophe "H."
很快就能划上句号的了
Well, makes a good ending.
Couldn't have done better myself.
这案子很快就结束的
I guess that closes that case pretty final.
当然不用太担心那案子
Sure does.
Never cared much for that case.
我今天可要饱餐一顿啦
Well, I think I'll go get ready for dinner.
I'm hungry. I can eat a good dinner today.
查莉有好消息通知你
哪里能聊几句?
Charlie, I have great news for you.
Where can we talk alone?
缅因州通知结束案子
你也能解脱了
We got a wire from Maine. We can call
off the job. I'll bet you're relieved. I am.
噢解脱了
Oh, I am relieved.
还游说你叔叔离开这
他肯定说你疯了
You were trying to get youruncle out.
He must have thought you were crazy.
一切都结束了
我不想再提了
Now that it's over, I don't
want to talk about it any more.
我希望假装
这一切没发生过
I'd like to pretend the whole
dreadful thing never happened.
-你不需要假装啊
-妈妈的手套
- There's nothing to pretend about.
- There's mother's gloves.
她总是丢三落四的
Mother and her gloves.
She's always losing things.
迟早\'她连你也会失去的
All mothers lose things.
Someday, she'll be losing you.
她才没有损失呢
还多了一个女婿
Mothers don't lose daughters,
they gain sons.
也是但事情
总不那麽如意譬如我吧
Yes, but gain isn't always the word.
Now, take me.
谁想要个侦探做女婿?
Who'd want a detective
for a son-in-law?
-我爸爸会
-他会?
- My father would.
- He would?
如果你说要嫁给侦探
他会怎麽反应?
If you told him you were going to marry
a detective, he wouldn't disown you?
不一定是我啊
可以是安妮
It wouldn't have to be me. There's Ann.
不她跟我说要
嫁给图书管理员
No, Ann wants to marry a librarian.
She told me.
所以她经常读那麽多书
So she'll always have
plenty of books around to read.
什麽事了?
What's the matter?
我好久没这麽开怀地笑了
I was laughing.
It's been so long since I laughed.
我喜欢你笑的样子
I like it when you laugh.
我喜欢你做的每件事
I like it when you don't.
I guess I like you whatever you do.
-我喜欢你
-我也喜欢你
- I guess I like you.
- I'm glad. I like you too.
有趣的是你遇见一个人
然後...爱上她
Funny how you happen to meet someone
and like them and... like them.
嗯
Mm-hm.
-查莉?
-什麽事?
- Charlie?
- Yes?
我想有天你会
跟你爸爸说--
I suppose it couldn't ever really happen
some day that you'd tell your father...
要嫁给一个侦探
You know, about marrying someone,
a detective, I mean.
-我不知道
-我也不想现在告诉你
- I don't know.
- I didn't mean to tell you.
我想等你把这一切
不愉快的事忘记
I wanted to wait until you'd forgotten
the mess we've been through together,
直到你想起
我不再有恐惧和不安
till you didn't think of me as part
of something unpleasant and frightening.
我希望能回来告诉你
I wanted to wait and come back
and then tell you.
但我想现在就跟你说
But I can't help it.
I want to tell you now.
查莉我爱你
I love you, Charlie. I love you terribly.
你介意我现在才说吗?
I know it's no time to tell you now
and I'm sorry. Do you mind?
-我不介意
-你会考虑一下吗?
- I don't mind.
- Do you think you could think about it?
-关于你爱我?
-也许你也爱我
- About your loving me?
- And perhaps your loving me?
我希望保持朋友关系
我们是朋友
I- I'd like us to be friends. I know that.
We are friends.
-我想保持现状
-没有其他吗?
- I'd like to have that to think about.
- Nothing more?
我不知道杰克
我...还不知道
I don't know, Jack.
I... just don't know yet.
好吧
但我能回来看你吗?
Alright. But I may come back?
噢当然能一定要回啊
Oh, please come back.
Please come back.
听著查莉
Listen, Charlie.
我去到市中心的广场
When I go, go back to that square
in the middle of town.
那是我们初次认识的地方
Take a good look at it.
That's where I first knew I loved you.
真是不打不相识
That's where we had the fight
and I didn't know what to do.
我热爱我的工作
只是那晚不喜欢
I like my job,
but I didn't like it that night.
那晚我讨厌它
I hated it that night.
-你现在讨厌它吗?
-不
- You hate it now?
- No, not now.
这像口井
我要弄个装饰品上去
You know, this is a swell place.
I'm going to put a bronze plaque up.
这门老是自己锁上!
That door's always banging shut!
噢!大力点!
Oh! It sticks.
啊!
Uh!
你们把自己锁在车房干嘛?
What are you two locking yourselves
in the garage for?
-我年轻的时候是在会议室
-奥克里先生
- When I was young, it was the parlour.
- Hello, Mr Oakley.
-我在跟查莉说再见
-在车房里?
- I was saying goodbye to Charlie.
- In the garage?
门被锁上了
现在我也要跟你说再见了
The door got stuck.
Now I'll have to say goodbye to you.
我们在草坪上道别好了
不用回到车房
Let's say goodbye out here on the lawn.
No use taking a chance on the garage.
-完了吗?
-完了我会再回来的
- Finished here?
- All finished, but I'll be back.
-很快就见到我的
-噢?
- You ' II be seeing me around.
- Oh?
不是因为公事
Not on business, though.
我明白
查莉是一个好女孩
I can understand you coming back.
Charlie's a fine girl.
她是我见过最好的女孩
She's the thing I love most in the world.
说真的格翰警官
一帆风顺
I mean it. Have a nice trip, Mr Graham.
下次不要乱拍照了
And don't take any more photographs
without permission.
你知道这是人权啊?
Rights of man. You know, freedom?
我们下次再讨论这个吧
We'll have a talk
about freedom some day, Mr Oakley.
-再会
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
-记得给我写信
你有我地址吧-嗯
Don't forget to write.
Remember, you have the addresses.
杰克!
Jack!
还有吗?牛油水果
蔬菜还要去图书馆
Anything else? I've got butter, fruit,
green thread and go to the library.
买些新鲜的
如果还有我会叫安妮去
And whatever vegetable looks freshest.
If I've forgotten anything, I'll send Ann.
好的
Alright.
妈妈!
Mother!
查莉!亲爱的!
你没事吧?
Charlie! Darling! Are you hurt?
我绊倒了
I tripped.
在哪里?弄伤了膝盖吗?
Oh, what is it? Is it your ankle?
没什麽事
我扶住了栏杆
I don't think I'm hurt.
I grabbed the banister.
噢你差点没命了!
You might have been killed!
每次孩子们走这楼梯
我都很担心
I worry myself sick every time
one of you comes down these stairs.
太陡峭和有点摇摆
要去修理一下
They're too steep and rickety.
They ought to be fixed.
你真的没事?
Are you sure you're all right?
查理叔叔
你什麽时候走?
When are you leaving, Uncle Charlie?
查莉一切都结束了
我想忘记它
Oh, come now. That other business,
it's all over. I'd like to forget it.
-我们现在很开心啊
-你什麽时候走?
- We're all happy here.
- When are you leaving?
我不会走的
I'm not going, you see.
暂时还不会
Not yet. I'm not going.
我想在一个熟悉的环境里
安定下来
I want to settle down. Live somewhere
people know me. Put some money by.
而且成为这个家的一分子
- Start a business. Be part of the family.
- I see.
-我知道了
-乖乖跟我做朋友吧
The most sensible thing for you to do
is to be friends with me.
我愿为你做一切事情
I can do a lot for you, Charlie,
for all of you.
不我们不要你的帮助
No, not you.
We don't want anything from you.
-我真希望向妈妈揭穿你
-我知道你想什麽
- I wish I'd told my mother about you.
- I know what you've been thinking.
你知道她会怎样吗?
她感受如何?
How would your mother have felt?
What would it do to her now?
你爸爸呢?
他在银行的差事呢?
How about your father?
His job at the bank?
如果这一切都没有了
你又怎麽样?
What would become of all of you
if everything came out?
你不用害怕
我不能告诉他们
You needn't be afraid. I can't tell them.
我才不怕呢
你能向谁说?谁相信你?
But I'm not afraid. What would you tell?
Who'd believe you?
你脑子里都是想著华尔兹
A waltz runs through your head.
你从戒指上的刻字
联想到报纸的新闻
You don't like the initials on a ring and
connect it up with a newspaper clipping.
-你甚至连戒指也丢了
Now, you haven't even got the ring.
I don't know what became of it.
-你拿了
我?
- You have it.
- I?
我送给你了
I gave it to you.
我不要你在这
不要你碰我妈妈
I don't want you here, Uncle Charlie.
I don't want you to touch my mother.
快走--我警告过你
不然我会亲手杀了你
So go away, I'm warning you.
Go away, or I'll kill you myself.
看见了吗?
这就是我对你的感觉
See? That's the way I feel about you.
-给你祖
-噢香水
- Here you are, Joe.
- Oh, perfume.
-清新芬芳的熏衣草
-我知道
- Just the fresh, clean smell of lavender.
- Yeah, I know.
-你们都那麽英伟
You look very handsome, both of you.
-我真为你们感到自豪
-艾玛你也很迷人
- I'm proud of the two men in my family.
- Emmy, you're a dream.
-别在孩子们说这话
It's a pity the children
have to sit on our laps.
这裤子有点麻烦
It's going to be a tight squeeze.
It won't do my pants any good.
-祖我想你来开车
-我们这样分配
- Joe, I wish you could drive.
- We do it this way.
-查莉你坐--
-查理叔叔可以跟爸爸坐後面...
- Charles, you'll sit -
- He can sit in the back with Dad.
-孩子们坐在旁边
-不可以
The children can fit in beside them.
你们都上出租车...
Nonsense. I'm getting a cab.
You all go in the taxi.
-查莉和我开车
-不查理叔叔你坐出租车
- Charlie and I'll go in the car.
- No, Uncle Charlie, you go in the taxi.
我要坐出租车!
I want to ride in the taxi!
当然可以
就这麽定吧
Course you do. So it's all arranged.
-查莉去车房把车开出来
-我想全家人坐车
- Charlie, run out and get the car.
- I'd rather drive the family.
我想你在途中听听我演讲
给点意见
I want you to hear my speech
on the way. You're my severest critic.
安妮
打电话叫辆出租车来
Anyway, we need a taxi.
Ann, go call Mr Abercrombie.
妈妈!
Mother!
妈妈带上我
爸爸坐出租车也可以!
Mother, please ride with me.
Father can take the children. Please!
我肯定是全场
穿得最糟糕的人
Bet I'll be the only man outside
of Charles fool enough to dress up.
不会了你穿得很体面
Then you'll be the only other on e
to be correct. You look distinguished.
查理你准备好了吗?
祖你去哪?
Charles, are you all ready? Joe, are you?
等等!
我把外套带上
Wait a minute!
I've got to get my overcoat.
噢亲爱的快点!
Please, dear. Hurry!
别急他们没见到
我是不会开始的
Take your time, Emmy.
They can't start till I get there.
这里有点冷
It's getting chilly in here.
这里是圣罗莎
KSRO, Santa Rosa,
加州的新闻联播
with studios in Vallejo
and Santa Rosa, California.
放点音乐吧
May as well have a little music
while we wait.
俄勒冈州警察局
把研究范围缩小
Oregon State Police pressed theirsearch
today for five -
噢!一定要那麽大声吗?
Oh! Does it have to be so loud?
把低音听清楚点
Gets the lower tones better.
我喜欢大声点!
太小声我听不到!
I likeit loud! If the music's too soft,
I can't tell what they're playing.
如果我有一支乐队
肯定要组成87人
If I have a band,
I'm a-least have 87 men.
救命!有人被困在车房
Help, everybody!
Somebody's caught in the garage.
那里令人窒息!
那门开不了
They're suffocating!
There's something wrong with the door.
祖!
Joe!
让我来抱她
I'll take her. I've got her.
祖从我衣柜里
拿瓶酒来快点
Joe, there's some whisky on my bureau.
Get it quick.
-查莉查莉
-查莉?
- Charlie. Charlie. Dear Charlie.
- Charlie?
艾玛擦擦她的腿
罗杰给她扇凉
Emmy, rub her feet.
Roger, run get something to fan her with.
查莉!
Charlie!
安妮不要这样
Ann, don't, dear.
查莉?查莉
你想说什麽?
Charlie? What are you trying to say?
走开
Go away.
艾玛她需要你
Emmy, she wants you.
我在这
亲爱的妈妈在这
I'm here, darling. Here's mother.
That's right, my baby.
没事了
你真勇敢来...
That's right, my brave little girl. Here.
-喝一口
-不--我没事
- Take a little sip of this.
- No, I'm all right.
-祖叫菲利医生来
-我没事只想站起来
- Joe, call Dr Phillips.
- No, I'm all right. I just want to get up.
查莉你很走运
有人把车开著
You had a wonderful escape. Someone
must have left the motor running.
-我找不到钥匙关上它
-我进去时找到了
- I couldn't find the key to turn it off.
- The key was there when I went in.
幸亏我路过
Lucky thing I passed by.
她差点没命
全靠你知道该怎麽做
She might have died. You saved her.
You knew just what to do.
-我也不知道怎会经过
-把演讲取消吧
- Don't know how I happened across her.
- We'll put the lecture off.
不你们都快去车来了
Oh, yes, there is. I want you all to go.
There's the cab now.
噢不行我要在这
Oh, I couldn't. I just couldn't go.
谁在车房发现我?
Wh-Who found me in the garage?
贺博听到你在拍门
Herb heard you beating on the door.
我在後院经过
听到拍门声
I was coming across the backyard
and I heard gaspin' and bangin'.
我就知道里面肯定有人在
I figured there must be
a human bein' in there.
-贺博真聪明
-真幸运
- Quick thinking, Herb.
- Lucky thing.
贺博你刚好
经过救了我
I'm glad you happened
to be going by, Herb.
来妈妈
Come on, Mother.
我-我想陪你
I- I want to stay with you.
我不想演讲了
一想到查莉有危险
I don't feel like making a speech now,
when I think what might have happened.
我没事
坐下来歇会儿就行了
I'm all right. I just want to sit
on the porch a while and get the air.
不亲爱的让我陪你
No, darling, I won't hear of it.
真的没事
我在家准备晚会了
I'm alright, really. I'd rather stay home
and get things ready for the party.
亲爱的让我留下来
Darling, I want to stay with you.
贺博你带罗杰好吗?
安妮跟我们坐
Herb, will you take Roger?
Ann, you come with us.
真奇怪
首先是楼梯有意外--
I just don't understand it.
First the stairs and...
格翰先生不在?
Mr Graham isn't there?
是弗雷斯诺的
史都华旅馆吗?
This is the Hotel Stewart in Fresno,
isn't it?
你没见过他?
And you don't expect him?
那好了谢谢你
I see. Thank you.
他不在?
谢谢再见
He isn't there?
Thank you very much. Goodbye.
你能告诉我怎样找到他吗?
Can you tell me where I can reach him?
我已经用他留下的地址找他
I've already tried to get him
at the address he gave me in Fresno.
谢谢
Thank you.
妈妈我能吃三文治吗?
Mom, may we have some sandwiches?
不要在客厅拿东西吃
去厨房
Don't take anything from the dining room.
Go in the kitchen.
让我来拿大衣--
Please go. And just leave your coats...
祖你来招呼大家吧?
Joe, dear,
will you take care of everyone?
查莉!
Charlie!
我下来了
I'll be right down.
啊...现在...
Well... now... hm.
奥克里先生
我还想香槟只在打仗时喝
Now, Mr Oakley. I thought champagne
was only for battleships!
我和妻子都不要了
你们喝吧
None for me, nor I'm sure, for my wife.
But we hope you'll all forget we're here.
让我们来乾杯--
查莉还没下来吗?
I'd like to propose a toast to...
Isn't Charlie coming down?
她就下来了波特太太
She'll be down in a moment.
Mrs Potter.
别吃那个
我弄马铃薯仅为了调味
Not that one. Why do I make tomato?
They always soak through the bread.
试这个有小麦面包
奶油和辣椒
Try one of these. It's whole wheat bread
and cream cheese. Paprika makes it pink.
-格林先生
-格林太太你呢?
- Mr Greene.
- Mrs Greene, what would you like?
谢谢
Thank you.
-我也要乾杯
-艾玛
- I think I'd like to propose a toast, too.
- Emmy.
为我们的访客
近年来最好的演讲者
To our distinguished visitor, who made
the best speech heard in town for years.
为奥克里先生乾杯
To that very good fellow, Mr Oakley.
-贺比
-谢谢
- Herbie.
- Thank you.
我们没有什麽
美国的演讲者
We don ' t get many American speakers.
也许外来的才是最好的
Seems like foreigners
make the best talkers.
啊她来了我们来乾杯
Ah, here she is. Now for my toast.
查莉...
Charlie...
你来得正好
You're just in time for a farewell toast.
我不得不宣布
明天我会离开这
I hate to break the news to you like this,
but tomorrow I must leave Santa Rosa.
-暂时离开
-真巧合
- Not forever.
- If that isn't the strangest coincidence.
-我明天准备去三藩市
-查理
- I'm off to San Francisco.
- Charles?
噢艾玛
我也不想打扰大家的雅兴
Oh, Emmy darling,
I didn't mean to spoil your fun tonight.
我收到通知
明早\'要赶火车
I got a letter today.
I have to catch the early morning train.
艾玛我会想念你
I'll miss you, Emmy.
我觉得这个小镇的人...
But I want you all to know
I'll always think of this lovely town...
都很热情好客...
as a place of hospitality
and kindness...
令我有家的温暖...家
and homes... homes.
-查理我不想你走
-艾玛我会回来的
- But I can't bear it if you go, Charles.
- Oh, Emmy, I'll be back.
我还有建造
孩子们的医院呢
I've arranged with Dr Phillips
for our little memorial for the children.
不是你要做什麽
It isn't any of the things you've done.
只是我们好不容易才一起!
It's just the idea
that we were together again. I'm sorry.
我们从小相依为命
But you see,
we were so close growing up.
後来查理走了我嫁人了--
And then Charles went away,
and I got married, and...
大家都知道後来怎样
Then, you know how it is.
身为人妻
就变得很健忘了--
You sort of forget you're you.
You're your husband's wife...
我们把你看成
是这里的一分子
We'll be looking for you. We feel
you're one of us, don't we, Margaret?
是啊你也是俱乐部的成员
Indeed. I want to thank you
on behalf of our club.
很感谢你给医院的礼物
And bless you
for your gift to our hospital.
-孩子们以後会感激你的
-谢谢你
- The children will bless you, too.
- Thank you, sir.
打扰了但我
我听到火车来了
Excuse me, sir,
but I-I can hear the train coming now.
不好意思
Excuse me.
查理上车吧
Better get aboard, Charles.
大家後会有期
罗杰安妮跟我来
Alright. Goodbye, everybody.
Roger, Ann, come see the train.
查莉来啊
Come on, Charlie.
You can see they get off.
好吧
Alright.
我想看看包厢
I want to see the rooms,
the private ones.
我见过卧铺
还睡过上层呢
I've seen berths. I've slept in two uppers
and one lower with papa.
-再见祖
-再见查理
- Goodbye, Joe.
- Goodbye, Charles.
-再见艾玛
-再见记得写信!
- Goodbye, Emmy.
- Goodbye. And don't forget to write!
我会的你也要啊
I will. You write too.
I'll send you my address.
再见
Goodbye.
不要在座位上跳来跳去
Don't jump on the seats, Roger.
罗杰听到吗?
Roger, what did I tell you?
还有一个箱子
能帮我拿来吗?
Porter, there's one more bag
in the other car. Will you get it, please?
查莉车要开了
我可不想留下来
Charlie, the train's going to start.
I don't want to get carried away.
太迟了!
我要快点下去!
Maybe it's too late!
Maybe I'll have to go along!
我们就跟著来
There's plenty of time.
You run along, we'll follow.
查莉
Charlie.
等等
Just a minute.
我想告诉你
让我离开是明智的
I want you to know
I think you were right to make me leave.
为你妈妈，对大家都好
It's best for your mother,
best for all of us.
你看到昨晚她的反应了
You saw what happened
to her last night.
她不够坚强
我想她不能承受这打击
She's not very strong, you know.
I don't think she could stand the shock.
-记得当她还是个孩子
-火车开了!
- I remember once, when she was little -
- The train's moving!
听着查莉，忘记我的过去
Listen, Charlie.
I want you to forget all about me.
忘记所有
Forget that I ever came to Santa Rosa.
你的手!
Your hands!
查理叔叔
放手!让我走!
Let me go, Uncle Charlie! Let me go!
查莉我不想的
I've got to do this, Charlie...
但你知道的太多了
so long as you know
what you do about me.
没到时候等车再快点
Not yet, Charlie. Let it get a little faster.
再快点
Just a little faster.
快点
Faster.
现在!
Now!
圣罗莎失去了一个好儿子
Santa Rosa has gained
and lost a son,
一个她引以为荣的儿子
a son that she can be proud of.
勇敢慷慨善良
优秀的人格
Brave, generous, kindly.
With all of the spendid dignity -
杰克你来了真好
I'm glad you were able to come, Jack.
我想找人倾诉
I couldn't have faced it
without someone who knew.
-我知道很多但不能对你说
-我明白
- I did know more. I couldn't tell you.
- I know.
他认为这世界是很可怕的
He thought the world was a horrible place.
-他从来没有快乐过
-没有
- He couldn't have been very happy ever.
- No.
他不相信身边任何人
He didn't trust people.
He seemed to hate them.
他憎恨这个世界
He hated the whole world.
他说过，像我们这样的人...
You know, he said that people like us
不知道外面的世界是怎样
had no idea what the world was really like.
也不是那麽糟糕
Well, it's not quite as bad as that,
只是做人要留个心眼
but sometimes it needs a lot of watching.
有时人也会走向极端
It seems to go crazy every now and then.
像你的查理叔叔
Like your Uncle Charlie.
他高尚的灵魂讨人喜欢的性格，永远与我们同在
The beauty of their souls, and characters live on with us forever.
佳家高清，国内最全最新高清影视资源库就在您身边！
请加QQ：1073737340获取最新高清影视目录，谢谢！